<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251" ?>
<string_table>




 <string id="gravartsmnb2_0"> 
 <text>I need a strong gravitational artifact...</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="gravartsmnb2_1"> 
 <text>Alright. Give me the device and the money.</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="gravartsmnb2_2"> 
 <text>...</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="gravartsmnb2_3"> 
 <text>And it's done! Here is the artifact.</text> 
 </string> 




 <string id="gravartsmnb_0"> 
 <text>What kind of artifacts do you have here?</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="gravartsmnb_1"> 
 <text>Yes, I have a special device... It's for artifact transmutation: if you take this device and put the required artifacts inside it it will turn them into a new artifact, but it currently has only a recipe for a strong gravitational artifact. I can provide the ingredients for the conversion; you only need the device itself and 5000 rubles.</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="gravartsmnb_2"> 
 <text>After I get the artifacts?</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="gravartsmnb_3"> 
 <text>That's right.</text> 
 </string> 








 <string id="stgraugdhs_0"> 
 <text>Mmh, I need something..</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="stgraugdhs_1"> 
 <text>Yeah? What do you need?</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="stgraugdhs_2"> 
 <text>The gravity-powered shotgun. I think only you can make it...</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="stgraugdhs_3"> 
 <text>Yeah, okay. I need a specific artifact - one of those stronger gravity-based artifacts. Bring it here, and we'll talk.</text> 
 </string> 




 <string id="ribkaprstugdhs_0"> 
 <text>I've got the artifact.</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="ribkaprstugdhs_1"> 
 <text>For the shotgun? Alright, let me put this together... There you go.</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="ribkaprstugdhs_2"> 
 <text>...</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="ribkaprstugdhs_3"> 
 <text>Take your weapon and go.</text> 
 </string> 



 <string id="grartgraugdhs_0"> 
 <text>Mmh, I need something. I need a gravity-based artfiact.</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="grartgraugdhs_1"> 
 <text>We have it, and we can give it to you, but you need to give me a reason for me to give it to you.</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="grartgraugdhs_2"> 
 <text>What do you want?</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="grartgraugdhs_3"> 
 <text>The artifact I need - one of those stronger gravity-based artifacts. Bring it here, and we'll talk. It'll be a fair trade.</text> 
 </string>


 <string id="ribk22prstugdhs_0"> 
 <text>I have a question about the artifact you need.</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="ribk22prstugdhs_1"> 
 <text>Got it? Okay, there you go...</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="ribk22prstugdhs_2"> 
 <text>...</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="ribk22prstugdhs_3"> 
 <text>Get the artifact, please.</text> 
 </string> 





 <string id="zzgmetalkisghtikz_0"> 
 <text>Thank you, stalker.</text> 
 </string> 

 <string id="zzzzsngtfrghtikz_0"> 
 <text>Oh, shit... what happened to him?</text> 
 </string> 


 <string id="zzzzsnikz_0"> 
 <text>Hello.</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="zzzzsnikz_1"> 
 <text>Hi. Did you manage to find out anything about the missing group?</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="zzzzsnikz_2"> 
 <text>As you expected, the group was taken prisoner by Sin. I managed to save them.</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="zzzzsnikz_01"> 
 <text>Let me check something.. I'm detecting their signal on my PDA. I think they're already here. Thank you, stalker. You did great! As gratitude, I'll give you a car for free. It'll be near the bunker. Thank you again.</text> 
 </string> 




 <string id="prstugdhs_0"> 
 <text>I found what you asked for.</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="prstugdhs_1"> 
 <text>Really? Well, they're lucky you came by, haha.</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="prstugdhs_2"> 
 <text>Can you release them?</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="prstugdhs_3"> 
 <text>Yes. We'll let them go soon. We need to do something with them before we let them go.</text> 
 </string> 




 <string id="stugdhs_0"> 
 <text>Who do you have in the next room?</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="stugdhs_1"> 
 <text>Why do you care? We've got a group of scientists in there. They were in the wrong place at the wrong time, heh-heh. They came just in time for our ritual. The heads of those scientists will come in handy.</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="stugdhs_2"> 
 <text>Wait, you want their heads? No, no, that's not good. I need them alive. I'll buy them from you.</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="stugdhs_3"> 
 <text>'Buy'? We don't need money. If you really need them alive, bring us three heads and they'll be set free.</text> 
 </string> 




 <string id="hhhnikz_0"> 
 <text>Are there any well-paid jobs?</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="hhhnikz_1"> 
 <text>Mmh, yes. About a month ago, we sent four teams to different corners of the Zone for research. The first group died in the Cordon, somewhere around the tower. You discovered the remains of the second group at Shining Path. Another was killed here at the pillbox near the lake. We don't know much about the fourth one.</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="hhhnikz_2"> 
 <text>Go on.</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="hhhnikz_01"> 
 <text>All I know is they disappeared at Silent Hills. Do you know what kind of people live there? Sinners. They're real psychos. I do accept the possibility that they're at their base, and the possibility that they're still alive. If you make it to there, try to help our group. They're the only employees we have left. If you help us, we'll give you a special reward.</text> 
 </string> 






 <string id="silgrav_0"> 
 <text>Hello. Barkeep sent me. He has business.</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="silgrav_1"> 
 <text>Barkeep sent you on business? We've got some "business" too. Listen up - if you're gonna do business with us, get me one of those stronger gravitational artifacts.</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="silgrav_2"> 
 <text>I'll try. Where can you find those artifacts?</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="silgrav_01"> 
 <text>Near gravity anomalies. It's not your first day in the Zone, is it? After you sort things out, go look for one.</text> 
 </string> 



 <string id="psilgrav_0"> 
 <text>Take this artifact.</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="psilgrav_1"> 
 <text>Well done, stalker. I think we can work with you.</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="psilgrav_2"> 
 <text>Can we get to my business?</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="psilgrav_01"> 
 <text>Yes, certainly.</text> 
 </string> 



 <string id="yaabneayb_0"> 
 <text>Do you have any other work?</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="yaabneayb_1"> 
 <text>Have you ever heard of the 'Sinners'? They're truly terrifying - you'll know what I mean when you first run into them. It's rumored that they're holed up in the Silent Hills somewhere. People say that their leader isn't even human, and he's supposedly one of the first in stalkers who made it to the Zone. In short, this is one of the oldest groups in the Zone: they've been here since it appeared. Now, I know that at their base in the Hills, there is a vault with various secret documents inside it. I need you to go there and get me a specific document from that vault. Do you think you can do this for me?</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="yaabneayb_2"> 
 <text>I'll try, but I can't promise anything.</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="yaabneayb_01"> 
 <text>Thank you. Be careful with those Sinners.</text> 
 </string> 



 <string id="mnb_0"> 
 <text>Here, take the file.</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="mnb_1"> 
 <text>You were able to get the document from the vault at the Sinner's base? Good job, stalker. This will really help us in learning more about the Zone.</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="mnb_2"> 
 <text>What about the payment?</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="mnb_01"> 
 <text>Yes, certainly. Give me a minute... Here's your money.</text> 
 </string> 





 <string id="ggzxroz_0"> 
 <text>Look, I’ve got something. Would this fake eye be of interest to you?</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="ggzxroz_1"> 
 <text>Hmm, a rare thing in the Zone. I'll buy it for 500 rubles.</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="ggzxroz_2"> 
 <text>Here, take it</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="ggzxroz_01"> 
 <text>Interesting stuff. Thank you.</text> 
 </string> 




 <string id="zxrpozsskayb_0"> 
 <text>I have some bad news for you.</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="zxrpozsskayb_1"> 
 <text>What? What do you mean?</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="zxrpozsskayb_2"> 
 <text>I found your brother. He's dead. He's in the underground lab at Dark Valley.</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="zxrpozsskayb_01"> 
 <text>Stalker... Could you leave me alone, please? Thank you...</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="zxrpozsskayb_5"> 
 <text>Alright, I'll leave you alone.</text> 
 </string> 





 <string id="nzombar_koshak_start_0"> 
 <text>I found your cat.</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="nzombar_koshak_start_1"> 
 <text>Y-o-o-u, st-t-t-alker. Thank yo-y-you.</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="nzombar_koshak_start_2"> 
 <text>No problem, buddy.</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="nzombar_koshak_start_01"> 
 <text>T-t-t-th-eee sci-sci-scientists w-were he-he-here earli-li-er. I saw th-them at th-the co-co-cottage...</text> 
 </string> 



 <string id="zombar_koshak_start_0"> 
 <text>Are you a zombie? Are you human? Can you hear me?</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="zombar_koshak_start_1"> 
 <text>Yo-yo-you, s-s-st-al-stalker. He-he-he-help, pl-pl-please.</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="zombar_koshak_start_2"> 
 <text>What do you want?</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="zombar_koshak_start_01"> 
 <text>I ha-ha-had a c-c-cat, a b-bi-bi-big on-one. S-she was mu-my best fr-friend. Sh-she al-al-alwa-always hel-he-helped me. I lo-lost h-he-her. Fi-fin-find he-her, pl-pl-plea-please. Here... Somewhere in one of the co-co-cottages...</text> 
 </string> 






 <string id="svdodddkz_0"> 
 <text>You're from the Professor?</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="svdodddkz_1"> 
 <text>Yes. I'm interested in something...</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="svdodddkz_2"> 
 <text>You're interested in something? So am I. Those egghead bastards placed a radiation field from their damn psy-rig right in front of our base. Some of our comrades say that the radiation field is expanding, and it seems it'll reach our base soon. Those eggheads have some weird shit going on... We've traced the source to a house that's left to one of the roads at Silent Hills. I don't want to send any of my men there. The radiation there is so intense that all the grass has faded and evaporated. Go there and see if you can turn that shit off. We'll talk afterwards.</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="svdodddkz_01"> 
 <text>Damn... okay, I'll do it.</text> 
 </string> 





 <string id="dodddkz_0"> 
 <text>Hello. Are you the Doctor?</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="dodddkz_1"> 
 <text>Yes. I knew you were coming..</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="dodddkz_2"> 
 <text>I have a few questions.</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="dodddkz_01"> 
 <text>Hold on a moment, I need your help first, then I'll help you with your questions. Listen carefully: a stalker wandered into the swamp and he's already spent half a day at the fishing lodge. I'm worried about him. Bring him here, but don't let him inside. Let him sit on the porch. Grab the first-aid kit from the stove, you might need it. Also, you'll need to take something from him as payment for my services.</text>
 </string> 



 <string id="mzdodddkz_0"> 
 <text>Hey, how are you?</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="mzdodddkz_1"> 
 <text>Who's there? A stalker? I need help. I.. came from the Radar. The radiation there.. is intense...</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="mzdodddkz_2"> 
 <text>There's a doctor nearby. I think he can help you.</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="mzdodddkz_01"> 
 <text>A doctor?! Let's go...</text> 
 </string> 



 <string id="pdodddkz_0"> 
 <text>Doctor, I left him on your porch. He says he came from the Radar.</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="pdodddkz_1"> 
 <text>Let him rest there for a while. Go to him and find out where he's from, what faction he's with, and take a careful look at his equipment.</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="pdodddkz_2"> 
 <text>Ok, got it.</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="pdodddkz_01"> 
 <text>Wait, there's more. After you're done with the stalker, you need to go see a trader. His name is Toad, he recently settled at the Hills. You need to pick up a strange-looking container; it looks something like a small refrigerator. You'll need to bring it here. You'll get free treatment if you do this for me.</text> 
 </string> 


 <string id="dopdodddkz_0"> 
 <text>Who are you and where are you from?</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="dopdodddkz_1"> 
 <text>Me? I'm Leary. I was part of a group of stalkers that was going from Shining Path to the Radar, and we decided to take a shortcut near the old military warehouses. But something's wrong there... If you go there, your brain gets cooked inside your skull. I don't remember how I got here. I recall seeing the destroyed bridge and having to swim...</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="dopdodddkz_2"> 
 <text>I see you have nothing interesting on you. You've got a gun and a radio... The Doctor needs something, so he can take you in. He'll sell one of your things for money for medicine, while I'll be taking the other as payment.</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="dopdodddkz_01"> 
 <text>Yeah, okay...</text> 
 </string> 



 <string id="jopdodddkz_0"> 
 <text>Hello, Toad. Doctor sent me.</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="jopdodddkz_1"> 
 <text>You came from the swamps, eh? You're a tough one, Messer. I'll be honest, I didn't think you would last three days in the Zone, but here you are. Alright, here's the thing that Doctor wants.</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="jopdodddkz_2"> 
 <text>Damn.. how much does this thing weigh?</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="jopdodddkz_01"> 
 <text>Heh, did you think that it was made out of feathers? If you can't carry it, throw your stuff into the storage box, you can come back for it later. Don't worry about it, I'll keep your stuff safe.</text> 
 </string> 




 <string id="hjopdodddkz_0"> 
 <text>Doctor, I brought what you asked for.</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="hjopdodddkz_1"> 
 <text>Good. I need you to do one more errand for me, and then I'll answer your questions.</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="hjopdodddkz_2"> 
 <text>Alright...</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="hjopdodddkz_01"> 
 <text>The stalker is getting better. He said that he came from the city with a group of people. Maybe he's a member of some faction? Go to Shining Path and ask around the local clan, maybe they know something.</text> 
 </string> 



 <string id="zzhjopdodddkz_0"> 
 <text>Listen, have you ever heard about Leary?</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="zzhjopdodddkz_1"> 
 <text>Who? Ohhh, that guy. Yeah I know him. He disappeared along with a group at the Radar.</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="zzhjopdodddkz_2"> 
 <text>He's alive and currently is at the swamp Doctor.</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="zzhjopdodddkz_01"> 
 <text>Goddamn... and we already said goodbye to him, and now this... That's some good news! Well, tell the doc that we are extremely thankful. I think that the information he got there will be very useful.</text> 
 </string> 






 <string id="nnnnnikz_0"> 
 <text>I think I found the knife.</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="nnnnnikz_1"> 
 <text>Yes, that's it! Thank you, you've helped me a lot.</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="nnnnnikz_2"> 
 <text>You wanted to share information related to someone I'm looking for, right?</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="nnnnnikz_01"> 
 <text>Alright... You're looking for Strelok, right? Long story short, I heard from some stalker at the bar who was wearing some worn-out coat that Strelok had stashes all around the Zone. He supposedly had one at MedPribor and here, in the Rostok underground. Our boys are currently diggin' there and it is possible that the part of the tunnel that was closed before is now accessible. </text> 
 </string> 



 <string id="nloudmoth_0"> 
 <text>Is there any work you want done?</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="nloudmoth_1"> 
 <text>Yes. You need to find a knife in the Rostok underground that my friend lost. After you took care of that bloodsucker, stalkers began swarming the place looking for all kinds of shit. My friend was one of them and he lost the knife in one of the rooms.</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="nloudmoth_2"> 
 <text>I'll go take a look. What about payment?</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="nloudmoth_01"> 
 <text>I heard you're looking for someone. I think you'll find what I know useful. Bring me the knife, and we'll talk about it.</text> 
 </string> 



 <string id="loudmoth_0"> 
 <text>How are you, stalker? Were you the one who sent that SOS message?</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="loudmoth_1"> 
 <text>Yes, I need help... Fuck, I barely escaped from that military base. There's no military there.. Those "people" there aren't even human!</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="loudmoth_2"> 
 <text>What do you mean?</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="loudmoth_01"> 
 <text>I was going to the Bar with some friends. They followed us... And somehow they knocked us out. We were taken to their base, and they impaled my friend Seryoga on a pole. Someone who looked like their leader performed some sort of a ritual... I can't forget that terrible sight. I still feel sick thinking about it.</text> 
 </string> 



 <string id="device_pda_uchenyh_deadcity_desc"> 
 <text>The last PDA's last entry: - "Damn, the military is conducting a raid, and they're leaving no stone unturned." There is also information about the psy-installations at lake Yantar, the marshes, and Pripyat in the PDA's memory card. There are also mentions of a "Black Monolith" project, but detailed information is encrypted.</text> 
 </string>


 <string id="duudpomosnikz_0"> 
 <text>I think I found a group of scientists in the city.</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="duudpomosnikz_1"> 
 <text>What about them? Are they ok?</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="duudpomosnikz_2"> 
 <text>Well, no. They're dead. It seems that they hid in the attic of one of the houses when the city was being swept by military stalkers. Here, they had this PDA.</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="duudpomosnikz_01"> 
 <text>Well, okay. Thank you. Talk to our junior assistant. He might have some work for you... Damn it, our groups have had nothing but trouble lately.</text> 
 </string> 



 <string id="zuudpomosnikz_0"> 
 <text>Do you have any work for me?</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="zuudpomosnikz_1"> 
 <text>Nah... Or wait, actually yeah, I do. A week ago a group of our men went to Shining Path to study some anomalies there and disappeared. I don't have anyone to send to rescue them, but you appear to be experienced. You'll need to find them, or their bodies, and find the results of their studies, if there any. </text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="zuudpomosnikz_2"> 
 <text>OK. I'll try to find them.</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="zuudpomosnikz_01"> 
 <text>If you find anything bring it here, to the bunker.</text> 
 </string> 
 



 <string id="dpomosnikz_0"> 
 <text>Hey, take a look. It's this one, isn't it?</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="dpomosnikz_1"> 
 <text>What? You... You found it?! Where?</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="dpomosnikz_2"> 
 <text>One guy gave it to me. It doesn't matter. Take it. I see that this thing is very precious to you.</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="dpomosnikz_01"> 
 <text>Stalker... I'm at a loss of words! Thank you! I'll tell the professor to let you in right away!</text> 
 </string> 




 <string id="pomosnikz_0"> 
 <text>Greetings.</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="pomosnikz_1"> 
 <text>Huh? What do you want? The Professor isn't accepting visitors today. Turn around and get out of here!</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="pomosnikz_2"> 
 <text>Calm down, Barkeep sent me here. Why are you so nervous?</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="pomosnikz_3"> 
 <text>What?! Uh... she... she's gone, don't you get it?! She's completely gone... she disappeared in that damn lab in the Dark Valley! Ah, if I could only find the pendant that I gave her... A silver one...</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="pomosnikz_4"> 
 <text>...</text> 
 </string> 




 <string id="prpozsskayb_0"> 
 <text>Ok, I think this is the place.</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="prpozsskayb_1"> 
 <text>Yup. Thanks for your help, Messer. Here's your suit, you've earned it.</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="prpozsskayb_2"> 
 <text>Thanks.</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="prpozsskayb_01"> 
 <text>Oh and by the way, you see that guy? That's the main assistant. He's a bit unhinged, so remember to treat him nicely. His wife died recently... She got a pendant from him some time ago, but they didn't find it near her body. She died in some lab at the Valley... Now he dreams of that pendant... Kinda  creepy, huh? Anyways, once again, thanks for your help!</text> 
 </string> 





 <string id="pozsskayb_0"> 
 <text>Greetings, Zyablikov? What's going on?</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="pozsskayb_1"> 
 <text>Hello. Listen, Messer, would you lead me to the camp? I can show you the way.</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="pozsskayb_2"> 
 <text>Alright, let's go.</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="pozsskayb_01"> 
 <text>Great! When we get there I'll give you one of the suits.</text> 
 </string> 




 <string id="zsskayb_0"> 
 <text>Here's the documents.</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="zsskayb_1"> 
 <text>Uh huh... huh... I don't understand anything! What laboratory? He's alive? Why didn't nobody tell us? What is going on here?</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="zsskayb_2"> 
 <text>Calm down, doc. What about my suit?</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="zsskayb_01"> 
 <text>Sorry, I guess I got a bit carried away. It's time to go back to Yantar. Come to the mobile lab for your suit.</text> 
 </string> 




      <string id="zcddaqiyorbar_0"> 
 <text>Greetings. What's that suit you're wearing? Did you get it from the eggheads?</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="zcddaqiyorbar_1"> 
 <text>Yes, it's a scientific suit. Fully waterproof. It can protect from even the worst chemical anomalies! Want one? I'll get you one if you do something for me.</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="zcddaqiyorbar_2"> 
 <text>What do you want?</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="zcddaqiyorbar_3"> 
 <text>Me and my brother used to work in the factory. His name was Vania. One time we got into an argument over a petty issue. I got really angry and ran away for a long time. When I finally came back, I learned that the entire complex was evacuated. But here's the catch - Vania didn't come back home. The administration tried to play us like a damn fiddle - they said that he either escaped, or died on duty. Basically, they lied like the devil. The entire family has gone nuts. Then I got a letter from the Research Institute with an offer to take part in an expedition to the Zone. More specifically - to protect it. I wanted to deny the offer, but I've heard that the complex is also in the Zone, and I have nothing to lose. Long story short - if you go to the Rostok plant and find anything that mentions my brother or maybe even him, I'll give you my suit. Are you up for it?</text> 
 </string>
 <string id="zcddaqiyorbar_4"> 
 <text>Hm... alright. I'll try to find something about him.</text> 
 </string>





      <string id="cddaqiyorbar_0"> 
 <text>Do you have any jobs for me?</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="cddaqiyorbar_1"> 
 <text>Yes, I do. Behind the Rostok plant, near the dam, is some sort of living area. A Kamaz truck sits there. I want it brought here, but nobody wants to do it. </text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="cddaqiyorbar_2"> 
 <text>I can try to do it.</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="cddaqiyorbar_3"> 
 <text>I see that you're quite a brave stalker. Ok then. The Kamaz is waiting for you near the living complex. Bring it here, to the bar. Don't worry bout payment, I'll take care of it.</text> 
 </string>
 <string id="cddaqiyorbar_4"> 
 <text>OK.</text> 
 </string>



 <string id="casskayb_0"> 
 <text>I brought the truck.</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="casskayb_1"> 
 <text>Great job, here's your reward. Is the truck alright? Does it have any cargo left inside? Or maybe something else happened?</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="casskayb_2"> 
 <text>No, everything is all right... Except, there was a bloodsucker... It probably came from Rostok..</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="casskayb_01"> 
 <text>Alrighty then. I'll get someone to put the truck at the 'parking lot'. Thanks for your help, Messer.</text> 
 </string> 




      <string id="ddaqiyorbar_0"> 
 <text>Greetings! Are you looking for new fighters?</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="ddaqiyorbar_1"> 
 <text>You want to join our ranks? We're always searching for brave fighters like you!</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="ddaqiyorbar_2"> 
 <text>Yes, I do!</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="ddaqiyorbar_3"> 
 <text>If that's so, then we'll happily take you in! You are now officially a member of Duty! Here's your gear.</text> 
 </string>
 <string id="ddaqiyorbar_4"> 
 <text>Glory to Duty!</text> 
 </string>




 <string id="sskayb_0"> 
 <text>Listen, I need some of your radioactive bolts. You got any?</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="sskayb_1"> 
 <text>Well, alright, why not. 1000 RU for 8 bolts.</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="sskayb_2"> 
 <text>Alright, here's the cash.</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="sskayb_01"> 
 <text>For that kind of price?! Have you gone mad?!</text> 
 </string> 



 <string id="skayb_0"> 
 <text>Hey, what are those boxes you got here? You've got all of these artifacts too.</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="skayb_1"> 
 <text>Yeah, imagine this - some Freedomers in Rostok found 10 crates full of bolts! But these aren't regular bolts, they're radioactive bolts...  Basically, this should've been brought outside the perimeter a long time ago, but there's some delays with the delivery and shit, so I'm keeping them safe. And about these artifacts - I managed to synthesize them some time ago. I had a portable transmutator, and I still have some recipes in my PDA. If you're interested, talk to our leader at the mobile bunker in Yantar.</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="skayb_2"> 
 <text>Alright, good to know. Thanks.</text> 
 </string> 




<string id="arpr122_0"> 
 <text>I think I did it, Barkeep.</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="arpr122_1"> 
 <text>Hold on a second. Some stalkers brought someone from the Radar. He seems to be... A bit insane. Still, I think we can get some useful information from him that might shed some light on what's going on over there.</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="arpr122_2"> 
 <text>Alright.</text> 
 </string> 




      <string id="aqiyorbar_0"> 
 <text>Barkeep, something's wrong with your guy.</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="aqiyorbar_1"> 
 <text>Damn. Do you know what he's talking about?</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="aqiyorbar_2"> 
 <text>It seems like that his brain is completely fried. I need a first-aid kit, he seems to be on his last legs.</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="aqiyorbar_3"> 
 <text>Here you go. Try to get him to talk.</text> 
 </string>
 <string id="aqiyorbar_4"> 
 <text>Alright.</text> 
 </string>



	<string id="bar_ryaboy_job">
		<text>Meeting with a psycho</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_ryaboy_job_0">
		<text>Get information about the "Brain Scorcher" from Spotty</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_ryaboy_medik_job">
		<text>Get the first aid kit</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_ryaboy_medik_job_0">
		<text>Get the first aid kit from Barkeep</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_ryaboy_medik_job_1">
		<text>Give the first aid kit to Spotty</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_ryaboy_lisiy_talk">
		<text>Talk to Baldy</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_ryaboy_lisiy_talk_0">
		<text>Talk to Badly about Spotty</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_ryaboy_lisiy_talk_1">
		<text>Talk to Spotty</text>
	</string>



      <string id="bopb_0"> 
 <text>Greetings, Barkeep. Is this what you're looking for?</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="bopb_1"> 
 <text>Where did you get that from?! Hide it, quick! You don't show stuff like that around in front of everyone!</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="bopb_2"> 
 <text>Listen, in there I saw...</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="bopb_3"> 
 <text>Let's go to my office, we'll talk there.</text> 
 </string>
 <string id="bopb_4"> 
 <text>Alright.</text> 
 </string>




      <string id="qiyorbar_0"> 
 <text>Your man is dead.</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="qiyorbar_1"> 
 <text>Damn.. was there anything else? Was he the only one who died?</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="qiyorbar_2"> 
 <text>A few Freedom-associated stalkers were killed. It seems to be the work of a Controller, and I think that Controller decided to follow me.</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="qiyorbar_3"> 
 <text>Well, in that case we'll have to do it ourselves. Some Freedomers gave us a tip about a potential stash location. Here, on the bar territory. These are the two places we need to check. Let's go.</text> 
 </string>
 <string id="qiyorbar_4"> 
 <text>Alright.</text> 
 </string>




      <string id="iyorbar_0"> 
 <text>Hello. What do you need?</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="iyorbar_1"> 
 <text>Stalker! You're alive. I don't know how you did it, but here you are. How's your head doing? Are you feeling okay?</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="iyorbar_2"> 
 <text>Well, mostly. I am feeling a bit off, but I'm alive, and that's what counts. I don't think I'm going to become a zombie that's going to eat your brains anytime soon.</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="iyorbar_3"> 
 <text>That's great. Let's get to the point: you plan on going to the center of the Zone, right? I've got something that might be of interest to you. Duty has an "Igla" missile launcher; in the Zone, these are extremely rare. Other stalkers want it, so they keep it under lock and key. If you do a certain job for Duty, you'll get it for free. You need to go to Rostok. There's a warehouse, and on the roof, there's a man from Duty there. Talk to him, and decide if you want to do the job. Simple enough, right? If you do it, the the reward will be worth it.</text> 
 </string>
 <string id="iyorbar_4"> 
 <text>I see you're not the average stalker, Witcher. Alright, I'll go do it.</text> 
 </string>




	<string id="mil2_freedom_commander_common2_0">
		<text>Hey. I'm back.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil2_freedom_commander_common2_1">
		<text>Hey, stalker. How's the situation there?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil2_freedom_commander_common2_2">
		<text>That place is inhabited by a couple of zombies and rats, but it's quiet.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil2_freedom_commander_common2_3">
		<text>Good.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil2_freedom_commander_common2_4">
		<text>But when I approached the Rostok exit, a bloodsucker appeared. It looks like he followed me...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil2_freedom_commander_common2_5">
		<text>I see. Well, if it's like that, then I think we can get through to the factory.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil2_freedom_commander_common2_6">
		<text>What's the plan of action?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil2_freedom_commander_common2_7">
		<text>We need to get ready. We are waiting for the necessary equipment for now. When we are ready, I'll inform you. We might be at the factory waiting for you when I inform you.</text>

<!-- Òåêñòû äèàëîãîâ ñ ëèäåðîì Äîëãà -->
    <string id="bar_dolg_lider_di_2_0">
	    <text>Good morning, general!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_lider_di_2_1">
	    <text>What are you doing, stalker? Do you need something?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_lider_di_2_2">
	    <text>Hmm.. I do need something. That does explain why I'm here.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_lider_di_2_3">
	    <text>*awkward silence*</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_lider_di_2_4">
	    <text>I think I should leave, hehe.</text>
	</string>
    <string id="bar_dolg_lider_di_1_0">
	    <text>I have a couple of questions.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_lider_di_1_1">
	    <text>I'm listening.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_lider_di_1_2">
	    <text>How was your group formed?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_lider_di_1_3">
	    <text>Why are you at war with Freedom?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_lider_di_1_22">
	    <text>When one of the first major expeditions was sent to the Zone, which included scientists and a military detachment, no one at that time knew what the outcome would be. The expedition failed, and one of the military generals, General Tachenko, founded Duty. Many of his comrades died, so he vowed to destroy the Zone, which he regarded as a plague. We have been following this ideology for a long time, and we are not going to retreat.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_lider_di_1_33">
	    <text>That's simple - their ideology opposes ours, and therefore, our interests do not coincide. In the Zone, we resolve our differences with force.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_lider_di_1_333">
	    <text>It's just that simple, right?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_lider_di_1_3333">
	    <text>Did you expect me to explain to you why we're a just cause? What's the point? Everyone knows we're in open war with Freedom and that we don't take any chances.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_lider_di_1_666">
	    <text>Nevermind.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_lider_di_1_999">
	    <text>Okay. Well, I’m going.</text>
	</string>
	</string>


      <string id="vibebar_0"> 
 <text>Well, are you ready to go to the factory?</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="vibebar_1"> 
 <text>Yes. I notified Barkeep that we were going to Rostok. He said that there were a large group of mutants near the factory. Nevertheless, everything is ready. I think we can handle it.</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="vibebar_2"> 
 <text>Alright, let's go.</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="vibebar_3"> 
 <text>Let's get going.</text> 
 </string>

        <string id="olr_barman_bar_monsters_tree">
            <text>Kill the bloodsuckers</text>
        </string>
        <string id="text_olr_barman_bar_monsters_tree">
            <text>Listen, there's a bunch of bloodsuckers behind the Rostok factory. People never go to there, but it's best if we get rid of them. Can you go kill them?</text>
        </string>
        <string id="desc_olr_barman_bar_monsters_tree">
            <text>Kill the bloodsuckers.</text>
        </string>


        <string id="olr_barman_bar_monsters_tvo">
            <text>Kill the dogs</text>
        </string>
        <string id="text_olr_barman_bar_monsters_tvo">
            <text>Listen, there's a herd of dogs near this parking lot. People never go to there, but it's best if we get rid of them. Can you go kill them?</text>
        </string>
        <string id="desc_olr_barman_bar_monsters_tvo">
            <text>Kill the dogs.</text>
        </string>


        <string id="olr_barman_bar_monsters_one">
            <text>Kill the boars</text>
        </string>
        <string id="text_olr_barman_bar_monsters_one">
            <text>Listen, there's a herd of wild boars at this hill. People never go to there, but it's best if we get rid of them. Can you go kill them?</text>
        </string>
        <string id="desc_olr_barman_bar_monsters_one">
            <text>Kill the boars.</text>
        </string>


      <string id="vibbar_0"> 
 <text>I managed to get caught by a blowout at the MedPribor Institute. Do you mind telling me when the next one is going to happen?</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="vibbar_1"> 
 <text>You got lucky. That blowout wasn't very strong.</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="vibbar_2"> 
 <text>What? How? What do you mean by "wasn't very strong"?</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="vibbar_3"> 
 <text>These weaker types of blowouts do happen, but they don't happen often. The last time one of those happened was when a group of veteran stalkers managed to break through to the center of the Zone. I can't predict when the next blowout will happen because my equipment is acting up. Until my equipment is fixed, I can't give out any guesses.</text> 
 </string>

        <string id="olr_find_art_drunk_gun">
            <text>Find an LR-300 for the Dutyer</text>
        </string>
        <string id="text_olr_find_art_drunk_gun">
            <text>Can you please get me a specific gun? I'm looking for a LR-300. We have plenty of unused grenade launchers and optical sights in storage. We need some shooters to put them on.</text>
        </string>
        <string id="desc_olr_find_art_drunk_gun">
            <text>Find an LR-300 for the Dutyer.</text>
        </string>


        <string id="olr_find_art_osved_rour">
            <text>Find the Disintegrator artifact</text>
        </string>
        <string id="text_olr_find_art_osved_rour">
            <text>A scientific research group has placed an order for the "Disintegrator" artifact. That artifact has strange properties that the majority of people don't understand, so traders don't pay much for them, but scientists are looking for them.</text>
        </string>
        <string id="desc_olr_find_art_osved_rour">
            <text>Find the Disintegrator artifact for the informant.</text>
        </string>


        <string id="olr_find_art_drunk_dvaa">
            <text>Find the Mercury Ball artifact</text>
        </string>
        <string id="text_olr_find_art_drunk_dvaa">
            <text>I'm thinking of going to on a raid to the Garbage. It's not far from here, but as you probably know, the anomalies and radiation is there in abundance. I don't want to use up my remaining anti-radiation meds there. If you get me a Mercury Ball artifact from there, or from someplace else, I'll make it worth your while.</text>
        </string>
        <string id="desc_olr_find_art_drunk_dvaa">
            <text>Find the Mercury Ball artifact for the informant.</text>
        </string>


        <string id="olr_find_art_drunk_ine">
            <text>Find the Mercury artifact</text>
        </string>
        <string id="text_olr_find_art_drunk_ine">
            <text>I was sitting at the Duty camp in the Garbage, and I ran into a bunch of stalkers that had returned from a raid. One of them showed me something curious, and the stalker claimed he found it in the Radar. It was an artifact I've never seen before: a Mercury. I asked him, "Where did you find it?", and he claimed that you can find them if you look hard enough. Can you find one for me? I'm amazed by how they look.</text>
        </string>
        <string id="desc_olr_find_art_drunk_ine">
            <text>Find the Mercury artifact for the informant.</text>
        </string>


        <string id="olr_petr_tree_vert">
            <text>Find a Colt M1911 pistol</text>
        </string>
        <string id="text_olr_petr_tree_vert">
            <text>Listen, I got an order here from one of our veterans. He wants a Colt M1911. Those pistols are chambered for .45 ACP. Can you me one?</text>
        </string>
        <string id="desc_olr_petr_tree_vert">
            <text>Find a Colt M1911 pistol for the Duty trader.</text>
        </string>


        <string id="olr_petr_two_vert">
            <text>Find a Desert Eagle pistol</text>
        </string>
        <string id="text_olr_petr_two_vert">
            <text>Listen, I got an order here from one of our veterans. He wants a Desert Eagle. Those pistols are chambered for .45 ACP. Can you me one?</text>
        </string>
        <string id="desc_olr_petr_two_vert">
            <text>Find a"Desert Eagle pistol for the Duty trader.</text>
        </string>


        <string id="olr_petr_one_vert">
            <text>Find a USP pistol</text>
        </string>
        <string id="text_olr_petr_one_vert">
            <text>Listen, I got an order here from one of our veterans. He wants an “USP". Those pistols are chambered for .45 ACP. Can you me one?</text>
        </string>
        <string id="desc_olr_petr_one_vert">
            <text>Find a USP pistol for the Duty trader.</text>
        </string>


        <string id="olr_kill_krovo_quest_vtor">
            <text>Kill the bloodsuckers</text>
        </string>
        <string id="text_olr_kill_krovo_quest_vtor">
            <text>Some bloodsuckers came over to the forest to the east of the Duty outpost in Garbage. Apparently, they migrated from the Dark Valley. Destroy them.</text>
        </string>
        <string id="desc_olr_kill_krovo_quest_vtor">
            <text>Kill the bloodsuckers</text>
        </string>


        <string id="olr_tri_find_wpns">
            <text>Find an AIMS-74</text>
        </string>
        <string id="text_olr_tri_find_wpns">
            <text>Have you seen the soldiers with those strange rifles? Rumors are going around that the Ukrainian government is buying rifles from Romania in bulk. Supposedly, they are quite lethal. I received an order one of those rifles. My sources tell me that only the soldiers carry them. Bring one and I'll exchange it for a new AK-74.</text>
        </string>
        <string id="desc_olr_tri_find_wpns">
            <text>Find an AIMS-74 for the informant.</text>
        </string>


        <string id="olr_left_quest_dva">
            <text>Kill Digger</text>
        </string>
        <string id="text_olr_left_quest_dva">
            <text>Listen, there’s this guy in the Cordon… He came with a group from the Garbage. Our people took them out, and he was their leader. Basically, I have information that he’s the only one who survived, and now, he seems to be hanging around on the farm. You need to take him out. The faster, the better.</text>
        </string>
        <string id="desc_olr_left_quest_dva">
            <text>Carry out the informant's hit on Digger.</text>
        </string>

        <string id="olr_quest_stor_osved">
            <text>Find the "Magnet" artifact</text>
        </string>
        <string id="text_olr_quest_stor_osved">
            <text>Listen, a friend of mine asked me to get an "Magnet" artifact. Could you get it for me?</text>
        </string>
        <string id="desc_olr_quest_stor_osved">
            <text>Find the "Magnet" artifact for the informant.</text>
        </string>




      <string id="arbar_0"> 
 <text>Tell me about yourself.</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="arbar_1"> 
 <text>What can I say? I am an ordinary stalker, and I go on raids into the Zone. You can see how well that went today, damn it. Sometimes I help Freedom with supplies or provisions, things like that.</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="arbar_2"> 
 <text>Freedom?</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="arbar_3"> 
 <text>Well, some dudes formed a group like Duty and settled down in the abandoned city. They’ve got a base there. They have snipers on the roofs holding the line against the zombies that have started to stream from Yantar. They’re decent guys, to be honest.</text> 
 </string>

      <string id="iorbar_0"> 
 <text>Is this your buddy?</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="iorbar_1"> 
 <text>Well.. holy shit. The raid is now postponed. Apparently this bastard came from the Rostok factory. People say that there's a whole mutant den over there. No one goes there, but those mutants manage to come here anyway.</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="iorbar_2"> 
 <text>What are you going to do?</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="iorbar_3"> 
 <text>I don't know, stalker. I'll try to find someone willing to go help raid the place... I'll probably stay here, or in the bar. For now, you should go about your business. I might have something for you later.</text> 
 </string>
 <string id="iorbar_4"> 
 <text>Yeah, ok.</text> 
 </string>

      <string id="serbar_0"> 
 <text>Hello there! I haven't seen you around here before. I suppose you came here from the Garbage? Ha, ha! Of course you did! What a silly question. Listen, do you want to earn some money?</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="serbar_1"> 
 <text>Sure. I could use some money.</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="serbar_2"> 
 <text>I'll tell you what's going on. I had planned on going on a raid to the MedPribor Institute with someone - a newcomer. He agreed to carry a backpack with the loot for me while I watch our asses on the way back. I sent him to the apartment block opposite of mine so he could rest up while I go do some business during the night. I just woke up, but I haven't seen or heard from him. I'm worried. Do you want to help me check things out? I'll cover you in there if you decide to help.</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="serbar_3"> 
 <text>Alright, let's go do it.</text> 
 </string>
 <string id="serbar_4"> 
 <text>Sorry, I don't have the time for this.</text> 
 </string>

      <string id="karbar_0"> 
 <text>Are you dumb or something?</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="karbar_1"> 
 <text>Hey, calm down. What's going on here?</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="karbar_2"> 
 <text>This is your last warning, stalker.</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="karbar_3"> 
 <text>Go to hell...</text> 
 </string>



      <string id="narbar_0"> 
 <text>What ya need?</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="narbar_1"> 
 <text>Ah, nothing. I'm just checking around. What's up with this stalker? He looks awful.</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="narbar_2"> 
 <text>He's a rookie, came from the Garbage. He's new to the zone and he's not accustomed to the power of the local alcohol yet.</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="narbar_3"> 
 <text>Heh, alright then.</text> 
 </string>


      <string id="carbar_0"> 
 <text>I'd like to buy a car.</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="carbar_1"> 
 <text>No problem. I've got several vehicles for sale.\n \nZaporozhets - 1000 rubles. It's a bit beaten up, but it works. It's in a garage on the Bar territory.\n \nMoskvich - 2000 rubles. Some stalkers managed to bring this from Pripyat. It's nearly brand new! It's at Yantar in the car hangar. \n \nKamaz - 8000 rubles. This is a biggie. It's a solid vehicle, and it has good handling. It's on Bar territory. \n \nLada - 5000 rubles. You'll hit 130 on the road, but don't expect that kind of speed offroad. Also on Bar territory, in one of the garages. \n \nAnd the BTR - 15000 rubles. Don't ask where I got it from. It's on Bar territory. \n \nWhat do you choose? But first, show me that you've got enough money. If you don't have anything, then there's nothing to talk about.</text> 
 </string> 


 <string id="carbar_2"> 
 <text>Gimme the Zaporozhets.</text> 
 </string> 

 <string id="carbar_moskvi"> 
 <text>I'll take the Moskvich.</text> 
 </string>

  <string id="carbar_lada"> 
 <text>Give me the Lada.</text> 
 </string>

  <string id="carbar_kamaz"> 
 <text>I think the Kamaz will work for me.</text> 
 </string>


  <string id="carbar_btr"> 
 <text>I want the BTR.</text> 
 </string>


 <string id="carbar_3"> 
 <text>I've changed my mind. Maybe another time.</text> 
 </string> 








<!--Òåêñòû äèàëîãîâ ñ Áàðìåíîì-->
	<string id="bar_about_killers_0">
	    <text>We need to talk.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_about_killers_1">
	    <text>What's up?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_about_killers_2">
	    <text>In the Dark Valley, right outside the lab, some guys in blue suits attacked me.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_about_killers_3">
	    <text>In blue suits? Hmmm... It looks like someone wants you dead! But who and why I won't tell because I don't know!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_about_killers_4">
	    <text>Alright. If you'll get some info - tell me!</text>
	</string>
    <string id="bar_before_repair_0">
	    <text>Hey Barkeep, where did you get all this stuff you sell from?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_before_repair_1">
	    <text>Some of it is brought from outside the Zone, and the rest is brought by stalkers. We fix the stuff they bring and sell it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_before_repair_2">
	    <text>Can I also repair my stuff here?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_before_repair_3">
	    <text>Sure!</text>
	</string>
    <string id="bar_before_repair_4">
	    <text>That's cool, thanks.</text>
	</string>
    <string id="bar_trader_repair_0">
		<text>Can you fix something?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_trader_repair_1">
		<text>Listen, a stalker is working off a debt for me, he's a good technician. He can fix anything - guns and stuff are his passion. So what are we repairing?\n \nPossible repairs: </text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_trader_repair_2">
		<text>Fix the weapon in the first slot.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_trader_repair_3">
		<text>Fix the weapon in the second slot.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_trader_repair_4">
		<text>Fix up the armor.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_trader_repair_5">
		<text>Crap, I'm low on cash. Maybe another time.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_trader_repair_6">
		<text>Here, all fixed up and ready to go!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_trader_repair_7">
		<text>Take it, it's all fixed up!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_trader_repair_8">
		<text>Like new! Your worker's great at this! Tell him I said thanks.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_trader_repair_9">
		<text>Great job, really!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_trader_repair_10">
		<text>Can he fix something else, too?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_trader_repair_11">
		<text>Of course, he doesn't have much to do these days!\n\Possible repairs:</text>
	</string>
 <string id="bar_about_inmormer_0">
    <text>Who's that dude in the corner, the one with the coat?</text>
 </string>
 <string id="bar_about_inmormer_1">
    <text>That's the Informer, what about him?</text>
 </string>
 <string id="bar_about_inmormer_2">
    <text>He's kinda strange...</text>
 </string>
 <string id="bar_about_inmormer_3">
    <text>Maybe he's a bit strange, but he knows a lotta things! Talk to him, you can get a lot of info out of him!</text>
 </string>
 <string id="bar_about_inmormer_4">
    <text>Thanks for the advice.</text>
 </string>
 <string id="reward_for_dyatel_off_0">
    <text>The job is done! The Scorcher is off!</text>
 </string>
 <string id="reward_for_dyatel_off_1">
    <text>Great work, Messer! Now the road to the center of the zone is open! How hard was it?</text>
 </string>
 <string id="reward_for_dyatel_off_2">
    <text>It was really hard, but I managed to do it.</text>
 </string>
 <string id="reward_for_dyatel_off_3">
    <text>Anyway, for what you did, we decided to throw together some money for a reward for you. Here you go... And by the way, some stalker wants to see you. He wanted me to tell you that he will be at the Cordon, in Toad's bunker. That is all.</text>
 </string>
 <string id="reward_for_dyatel_off_4">
    <text>Thanks.</text>
 </string>


 <!--Òåêñòû äèàëîãîâ ñ Îñâåäîìèòåëåì-->
 <string id="questions_to_informer_0">
    <text>I'm interested in some information.</text>
 </string>
 <string id="questions_to_informer_1">
    <text>Ask away! I'll answer, but not for free, obviously. One answer - 100 rubles.</text>
 </string>
 <string id="questions_to_informer_11">
    <text>Where is the Freedom base located?</text>
 </string>
 <string id="questions_to_informer_12">
    <text>What's up with the radiation at Yantar?</text>
 </string>
 <string id="questions_to_informer_13">
    <text>What is the "Sin" faction?</text>
 </string>
 <string id="questions_to_informer_14">
    <text>Do you know where is the Sin base located?</text>
 </string>
 <string id="questions_to_informer_15">
    <text>Do you know where I can find the Journalist?</text>
 </string>
 <string id="questions_to_informer_16">
    <text>I'm looking for some normal armor, do you have any suggestions?</text>
 </string>
 <string id="questions_to_informer_17">
    <text>Who's the Journalist?</text>
 </string>
 <string id="questions_to_informer_999">
    <text>Gimme a hundred and I'll talk.</text>
 </string>
 <string id="questions_to_informer_9991">
    <text>Take it.</text>
 </string>
 <string id="questions_to_informer_9992">
    <text>I'll see you later.</text>
 </string>
 <string id="questions_to_informer_11111">
    <text>The Freedom base is located in the center of Shining Path. You can get there from the Silent Hills or from Yantar.</text>
 </string>
 <string id="questions_to_informer_12111">
    <text>It's psi-radiation, generated by an installation in the central complex. You can turn it off only in a lab hidden under the lake. The Yantar territory is very dangerous, one wrong step and you'll lose your mind!</text>
 </string>
 <string id="questions_to_informer_13111">
    <text>These guys have a dark past. Nobody knows where they're from, but some say that they're people who were in the perimeter at the time of the Second Incident. They rarely talk to anyone, most of the time they'll just kill and feed mutants with the corpse.</text>
 </string>
 <string id="questions_to_informer_14111">
    <text>In the Silent Hills, on the territory of the old army base.</text>
 </string>
 <string id="questions_to_informer_15111">
    <text>Last time he was seen on the roof of some house close to the Freedom base.</text>
 </string>
 <string id="questions_to_informer_16111">
    <text>Search around on the Garbage, if nobody already found it that is, he-he... I won't give back the money by the way. You asked for info - you got it.</text>
 </string>
 <string id="questions_to_informer_17111">
    <text>An experienced stalker. He came to the zone to get info about some event. In the past he was often seen by stalkers, but now nobody knows where he is. He worked with a stalker called Strelok, probably hired him as a bodyguard or something.</text>
 </string>
 <!---->
 <!--Òåêñòû äèàëîãîâ ñ Äîêòîðîì-->
 <string id="doctor_help_actor_0">
    <text>I don't feel so good, mind healing me up?</text>
 </string>
 <string id="doctor_help_actor_1">
    <text>You give me some food and I'll help ya.</text>
 </string>
 <string id="doctor_help_actor_11">
    <text>I've got some bread, here.</text>
 </string>
 <string id="doctor_help_actor_12">
    <text>I can share a sausage with you.</text>
 </string>
 <string id="doctor_help_actor_13">
    <text>I've got some canned goods.</text>
 </string>
 <string id="doctor_help_actor_92">
    <text>I've got nothing.</text>
 </string>
 <string id="doctor_help_actor_666">
    <text>Alright, sew up here... use some gel here... bandage this... All done! You're good as new!</text>
 </string>
 <string id="doctor_help_actor_667">
    <text>Okay, I'll help you for free for the first time. Alright, sew up here... use some gel here... bandage this... All done! You're good as new!</text>
 </string>
 <string id="about_doctor_0">
    <text>What do you do here, Doctor?</text>
 </string>
 <string id="about_doctor_1">
    <text>I help everyone who needs help, if they deserve it, of course.</text>
 </string>
 <string id="about_doctor_2">
    <text>That thing in the other room, is that your patient? Jeez...</text>
 </string>
 <string id="about_doctor_3">
    <text>For you stalkers - yes. That's why when you kill everything that moves, you hurt yourself to some extent. When killing a being, I advise you to think if that pain won't come back to you one way or another.</text>
 </string>
 <string id="about_doctor_4">
    <text>I'll try.</text>
 </string>
 <string id="how_went_to_zone_0">
    <text>Why did you come to the Zone?</text>
 </string>
 <string id="how_went_to_zone_1">
    <text>Unlike many I came here for knowledge and not money.</text>
 </string>
 <string id="how_went_to_zone_2">
    <text>Well, what do you live off of, then?</text>
 </string>
 <string id="how_went_to_zone_3">
    <text>In gratitude for my help, people bring me necessary things.</text>
 </string>
 <string id="how_went_to_zone_4">
    <text>Oh, okay.</text>
 </string>
 <string id="where_take_gift_0">
    <text>Why are the mutants friendly to you?</text>
 </string>
 <string id="where_take_gift_1">
    <text>The Black Monolith can do a lot more than that...</text>
 </string>
 <string id="where_take_gift_2">
    <text>The Black Monolith?!</text>
 </string>
 <string id="where_take_gift_3">
    <text>Yes, the Black Monolith. It really exists, but it does the wishes not exactly the way we would want them to be done. I won't say anything else on this topic, you will learn everything yourself with time.</text>
 </string>
 <string id="where_take_gift_4">
    <text>Alrighty...</text>
 </string>
 <!---->
 
 <!--OLR-->
 <string id="doll_0"> 
 <text>Did you want to see me? </text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="doll_1"> 
 <text>Yes, I've got something for you. One of our guys said that you were the one who killed the bloodsucker at Rostok. Great job, by the way. Anyway, I've got a job for you to do in that factory. You need to find a journal. You remember that stalker you found in the underground? Well, he was supposed to do that, but as we both know he didn't make it.</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="doll_2"> 
 <text>Alright, I'll try to find that journal.</text> 
 </string> 

 <string id="do_0"> 
 <text>Greetings stalker, are you new here?</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="do_1"> 
 <text>Yes, I recently came here from the Cordon.</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="do_2"> 
 <text>Look, I don't have time to chat right now. Come here later, or I will call you myself.</text> 
 </string> 


 <string id="dokg_0"> 
 <text>Ahh... shit... bloodsucker... help me, stalker!</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="dokg_1"> 
 <text>Hold on.</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="dokg_2"> 
 <text>Gimme a medkit. Duty will be grateful for you.</text> 
 </string> 

 <string id="serega_0"> 
 <text>Who are you?</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="serega_1"> 
 <text>What? And who are you? Look, I'm tired. I'm too tired to chat, I just came back from a raid. Come later, we'll talk.</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="serega_2"> 
 <text>Alright then.</text> 
 </string> 

 <string id="skay_0"> 
 <text>Greetings, Messer. I am a stalker from the Clear Sky faction. We aren't that great in numbers, so we work with loners. If you want to help us, come to the central complex of the MedPribor institute. Our guys are there. Help of someone like you will be of great use to them.</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="skay_1"> 
 <text>Clear Sky? That's the first time I hear about a faction like that. Alright, I'll meet with your people when the opportunity arrives.</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="skay_2"> 
 <text>Thank you, Messer.</text> 
 </string> 



   <string id="g_bar_0">
     <text>Were you the one who sent me that message?</text>
  </string>
   <string id="g_bar_1">
     <text>Yes. In all honesty, we automatically write off people like you. Mutants love fresh stalker meat. But I see that in your case it won't be that easy for them.</text>
  </string>
   <string id="g_bar_2">
     <text>I have a job to do.</text>
  </string>
   <string id="g_bar_3">
     <text>Hmm... what are you talking about?</text>
  </string>
   <string id="g_bar_4">
    <text>I'm looking for a part of some documents. According to my information, it should be located in this place.</text>
  </string>
   <string id="g_bar_5">
    <text>Yes, it is here. I can give it to you, but at a cost. You'll do some dirty jobs for me and you'll get your papers. Behind the base, near the entrance to the Bar some stalkers banded together. They're planning something. You must sneak up on them and figure out what they're planning, then you have to take them out. </text>
  </string>
   <string id="g_bar_6">
    <text>Crap... Alright. I hope you'll keep your word.</text>
   </string>
  <string id="g_bar_7">
    <text>Alright, go now, stalker.</text>
  </string> 


   <string id="st_dialog_0">
     <text>Greetings, Barkeep.</text>
  </string>
   <string id="st_dialog_1">
     <text>Hello, Messer! How are ya? Are you alright? Is your brain fried?</text>
  </string>
   <string id="st_dialog_2">
     <text>Everything seems okay. The installation is off, there is no more psi-radiation at the lake.</text>
  </string>
   <string id="st_dialog_3">
     <text>Great. Listen: according to the documents you brought from the Dark Valley laboratory, it seems that the Yantar installation generated a psi-field covering some other territory. Another, more powerful antenna: the Duga-1, protecting the road to the north. In theory the road to that antenna is now clear.</text>
  </string>
   <string id="st_dialog_4">
    <text>Go on...</text>
  </string>
   <string id="st_dialog_5">
    <text>Around the Radar, there is an entrance to an underground complex. That's probably where the Duga-1 controls are located. You'll need to get to that complex and turn off that thing. Then the road to the north will be open.</text>
  </string>
   <string id="st_dialog_6">
    <text>Hmmm...okay.</text>
   </string>
  <string id="st_dialog_7">
    <text>Also, there is a car parked outside the bar. It's old, of course, but I think it will be useful. Here, take the keys.</text>
  </string>  


   <string id="doc_bar_0">
     <text>Greetings, stalker.</text>
  </string>
   <string id="doc_bar_1">
     <text>Do you know who am I? Just don't tell me that the entire rumor with Messer - A.K.A me - came to you too.</text>
  </string>
   <string id="doc_bar_2">
     <text>Who's Messer? I don't know any Messer. I know my work and I can always recognize it. Hmm, that scar behind your ear... does it hurt, does it itch?</text>
  </string>
   <string id="doc_bar_3">
     <text>The only thing that itches me is my memory, or rather the lack thereof...</text>
  </string>
   <string id="doc_bar_4">
    <text>Well, I guess that's what happens after the Monolith.</text>
  </string>
   <string id="doc_bar_5">
    <text>To hell with the Monolith! Doctor, do you know who I am?!</text>
  </string>
   <string id="doc_bar_6">
    <text>Obviously. You were previously called Strelok. Listen, I can't help you enough to make your memories come back. You need to find the Journalist. He will answer all your questions.</text>
   </string>
  <string id="doc_bar_7">
    <text>What!? I am Strelok?!</text>
  </string>  




   <string id="stader_barh_0">
     <text>I've got the documents.</text>
  </string>
   <string id="stader_barh_1">
     <text>Great! Show them to me. Hmm... there is info in them about psi-installations located in the northern part of the zone. It looks like they are the obstacle. And there is also a mention that the scientists from Yantar were responsible for delivering parts and supplying these antennas.</text>
  </string>
   <string id="stader_barh_2">
     <text>Scientists? What are they doing there?</text>
  </string>
   <string id="stader_barh_3">
     <text>God only knows, they're apparently doing some experiments. I think you should talk to them.</text>
  </string>
   <string id="stader_barh_4">
    <text>Okay, I'll go to Yantar.</text>
  </string>
   <string id="stader_barh_5">
    <text>Remember that there are many psionic hotspots scattered around there. If you don't want to fry your brain, keep away from the central complex. By the way, you're going to Yantar... Take this artifact merger. Let it be a reward for those documents from the lab. Just know that there are no recipies saved in the memory. If you want any, you should ask the scientists.</text>
  </string>
   <string id="stader_barh_6">
    <text>Alright. How do I get to Yantar?</text>
   </string>
  <string id="stader_barh_7">
    <text>The road to Yantar is located here, at the Bar. It's that long road. When you leave the bar, immediately take the road to the south west. That's how you'll get to the lake. Also, don't forget about necessary equipment, otherwise you won't last long.</text>
  </string>  


   <string id="stader_bar_0">
     <text>Are you the Barkeep? Toad sent me to you with these documents.</text>
  </string>
   <string id="stader_bar_1">
     <text>Greetings, Messer. I haven't finished listening to the latest news about a Death Truck survivor who screwed up the military, but it turns out he's already here. Heh. Anyways, you're at the "Stalker" bar. This place is the "hub" of the Zone. Here you can rest and chat with other stalkers. Anyways, show me what you've got.</text>
  </string>
   <string id="stader_bar_2">
     <text>So, what is in those documents?</text>
  </string>
   <string id="stader_bar_3">
     <text>Mhm... there's some blueprints and calculations. There's also a mention of some laboratory, hidden under the Dark Valley. It looks like some kind of experiments took place there...  Listen, I think you will need to find that place and find more documents. What you brought isn't enough.</text>
  </string>
   <string id="stader_bar_4">
    <text>You want me to go down to a laboratory?</text>
  </string>
   <string id="stader_bar_5">
    <text>Yes, it looks like there's no other way. It is clearly said in the documents that the laboratory is hidden under the Valley.</text>
  </string>
   <string id="stader_bar_6">
    <text>Well If I have to go I'll go.</text>
   </string>
  <string id="stader_bar_7">
    <text>Messer, that Valley... that place... Stalkers rarely go there. I recommend getting a lot of ammunition, nobody knows what's waiting for you there. The entrance to the Dark Valley is located in the eastern part of the Garbage. Two paths lead there. Good luck to you, Messer.</text>
  </string>  









      <string id="sokolov_kvest_dialog_0"> 
 <text>Do you have any special jobs for me? I heard that some bloodsuckers have appeared here as of late.</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="sokolov_kvest_dialog_1"> 
 <text>Yup, there's one thing. You need to find and kill a bloodsucker in the Rostok factory. It appeared there some time ago. I'll have you know that we're trying to kill it for a  long time, but our efforts have so far been in vain. Many stalkers have lost their lives because of that leech. If you kill it then payment is guaranteed. </text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="sokolov_kvest_dialog_2"> 
 <text>I'll take care of it.</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="sokolov_kvest_dialog_3"> 
 <text>I think I'll pass.</text> 
 </string> 

 <string id="sokolov_kvest_dialog_completed_0"> 
 <text>The sucker is dead.</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="sokolov_kvest_dialog_completed_1"> 
 <text>Messer, damn me, you're alive! I can't believe that you killed that foul beast! I have a reward for you. Do you know where Duty has their headquarters? Across their base is a house. The stalker who occupied it disappeared a long time ago, I haven't heard of him in years. Here, take the key, you can live there. I haven't been in that house since it's owner disappeared, either way I don't need it and you've done a great thing. Take it. Ah, I've almost forgot: the leader of Duty wants to see you.</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="sokolov_kvest_dialog_completed_2"> 
 <text>A house? Interesting. Alright, thanks.</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="text_gavrilenko_kvest"> 
 <text>Find and kill the Rostok bloodsucker</text>  
 </string>



 <string id="barman_spam_dom">
 <text>Barkeep: How's the house? No ghosts bothering you? I'm joking, of course. I forgot to mention that the house has a safe inside it. You can keep your stuff in there.</text>  
 </string>





       <string id="rat_story_info_0">
		<text>Listen, I am looking for someone. Name's Strelok. Do you know him?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rat_story_info_1">
		<text>Strelok... Yes, I know something. I saw him and his crew at MedPribor once. Rumor has it he's gone missing. Some say that he disappeared near the power plant, others say that he disappeared behind it. I don't know exactly. It's kind of a weird thing with that Strelok guy...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rat_story_info_100">
		<text>Thanks.</text>
	</string>	







        <string id="ros_sos">
		<text>SOS Signal. Somebody, help me! Quick!</text>
	</string>

        <string id="ros_sos2">
		<text>Quick! I'm under the complex!</text>
	</string>



        <string id="mg_leader_hello">
		<text>This is the leader of Freedom. Talk to the trader on the 2nd floor, he has a job for you. We will talk later.</text>
	</string>




        <string id="escape_trader_oops_0">
		<text>Greetings, who are you?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="escape_trader_oops_1">
		<text>And who are you? We are a group of people with the same beliefs and interests. Some kind of clan. We organize raids together, raids that help everyone, kind of a friend self-help. This is our base.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="escape_trader_oops_2">
		<text>Okay. What are your beliefs and interests?</text>
	</string>

	<string id="escape_trader_oops_3">
		<text>Artefacts, of course! You can't do anything without them. And documents. You know, there are lots of laboratories in the Zone and there are tons of documents  inside them. They are worth quite a lot of money.</text>
        </string>

        <string id="escape_trader_oops_4">
		<text>Alright, see you.</text>
	</string>







        <string id="escape_trader_job_0">
		<text>Is there any work you want done?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="escape_trader_job_1">
		<text>Yes, there is. You need to bring me a TOZ-34.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="escape_trader_job_2">
		<text>Okay. Where do I look?</text>
	</string>

	<string id="escape_trader_job_3">
		<text>In the house nextdoor.</text>
        </string>

        <string id="escape_trader_job_4">
		<text>I'll look for it..</text>
	</string>





















	<string id="bar_arena_man_job_0">
		<text>Go on...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_arena_man_job_11">
		<text>So, your first fight? Your opponent is a piece of meat just like you. He's here because of debts and he only has two options: to come out and fight or to land himself in the nearest anomaly. He's gonna fight like a cornered animal. Equipment for today... lemme think... OK! Why don't you two use PMm's...two clips each should be plenty. Either you kick his arse or we feed you to the dogs - not much of a choice. Go on now.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_arena_man_job_111">
		<text>I'm ready.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_arena_man_job_112">
		<text>I'm not ready.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_arena_man_job_12">
		<text>Your last fight didn't mean shit. You're still the same piece of meat you were before and no self-respecting person will bet a single mag on you. If you wanna earn some proper cash you're gonna have to make a few more appearances in the arena. Your new opponent also got through the first round and his fight was a lot harder than yours. I don't like him, to be honest - he kills too quickly and the crowd doesn't like that. So, go and show us what you can do! The stakes will increase after this fight - all you gotta do is stay alive. Move it!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_arena_man_job_121">
		<text>I'm ready.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_arena_man_job_122">
		<text>I'm not ready.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_arena_man_job_13">
		<text>Well, well... You're not as much of a pussy as you first seemed. Now it's time to test you out in a real fight. You're up against two guys. The first one's called Swede and I don't remember the second one's name. They were paired up intentionally as they hate each other's guts so don't worry about them working as a team - they're more likely to shoot each other. Today is rifle day so don't let them get too close or we'll have to pick you up piece by piece. The odds are ten to one so if you win you'll make a fair amount. Off you go!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_arena_man_job_131">
		<text>I'm ready.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_arena_man_job_132">
		<text>I'm not ready.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_arena_man_job_14">
		<text>Well, now I can safely say that you're a fighter, a real fighter. Now it's time for a team fight. You get to fight with two rookies - two brothers - on your side. They haven't fought yet but they're brothers, so I had to put them into a team fight. I wouldn't expect any real help from them if I were you. You're fighting an experienced team, they're contenders for the final this season. A dangerous lot. They use different weapons but one has an automatic shotgun - be very careful with him. Good luck, pal... you're gonna need it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_arena_man_job_141">
		<text>I'm ready.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_arena_man_job_142">
		<text>I'm not ready.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_arena_man_job_15">
		<text>You've got a special fight today. Even the army has heard about you! Don't be surprised, they fight here too - there's even a general in the crowd. These guys are from the Spetsnaz or from OMON. They're well armed and their armor is good as you'd expect. Don't worry though, I ain't gonna leave you out in the rain, either. You'll get a vest used by Freedom - it's light so it won't slow you down. Go on, show them that stalkers ain't no whipping boys. Good luck!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_arena_man_job_151">
		<text>I'm ready.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_arena_man_job_152">
		<text>I'm not ready.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_arena_man_job_16">
		<text>Time for you to show what you can do. Duty captured a group of bandits that had been causing problems for stalkers near Rostok. Duty took 'em at night so most of the bandits were taken alive. They were all gonna be executed anyway so I convinced Duty to give them a chance. If any of them survive, they'll go in the can outside the Zone, which is better than dying here. They're not well-armed - just a few pistols and sawn-offs - but there's six of them so watch yourself. Go on now!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_arena_man_job_161">
		<text>I'm ready.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_arena_man_job_162">
		<text>I'm not ready.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_arena_man_job_17">
		<text>Well, you're almost in the final. Now you'll be fighting a real stalker. He's alone but he's got an FN2000 and he's inside an exoskeleton. Catch one burst and you're toast. There will be a surprise that I can't tell you about too... Here's my advice: be prepared, it's gonna be tough. The winner makes it through to the final. Fight to the death, go!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_arena_man_job_171">
		<text>I'm ready.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_arena_man_job_172">
		<text>I'm not ready.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_arena_man_job_18">
		<text>Congratulations, you're in the final! One more to go and this one is to the death, every man for himself. There will be four other stalkers in the arena: all real pros in exoskeletons with H&amp;K G36s but it's a fair deal this time - you'll get exactly what they have. The only thing is, you don't get medkits or bandages in a fight to the death. Ready? Go prove you're the best, GO!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_arena_man_job_171">
		<text>I'm ready.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_arena_man_job_172">
		<text>I'm not ready.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_arena_man_start_11">
		<text>Yo! I've got a new fight for you.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_arena_man_start_21">
		<text>Go have a drink or something. The Arena ain't ready yet.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_arena_man_start_31">
		<text>You've already become a pro!!!\nThere are no fighters good enough for you here, that's why I propose you should fight on the other arena - with mutants!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_arena_man_start_41">
		<text>You won! Here's your reward.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_arena_man_start_51">
		<text>You're not experienced enough for this fight.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_arena_man_start_61">
        <text>Greetings! I've got a new mutie for you. Want to fight him?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_arena_man_start_71">
        <text>What are you waiting for? Get in the cage.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_arena_man_start_81">
        <text>Sorry, there's nothing to fight right now. Wait a day or two, we should catch a new mutant by then.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_arena_man_start_91">
        <text>That's my boy! Here's your reward. If you want to fight for money again, come again.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_arena_man_start_101">
        <text>Sorry bro, but you've lost. Come again next time if you want.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="bar_arena_man_start_201">
        <text>Pussy!</text>
    </string>
	<string id="bar_arena_manager_game_0">
        <text>I want to fight. Who's the opponent?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_arena_manager_game_1">
        <text>There is nobody to fight right now. Come later when Duty will deliver a new shipment of mutants.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="bar_arena_manager_game_2">
        <text>There's a pseudodog. Quite a big one. A bit beaten up, but mad as my mother-in-law! Be thankful you've never seen her...</text>
    </string>
	<string id="bar_arena_manager_game_21">
        <text>I'll try. Let your mother, I mean dog, out.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_arena_manager_game_22">
        <text>Nah, I won't fight a dog.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_arena_manager_game_221">
        <text>Our little girl is too scared to fight a doggie. Alright, don't get mad, just banter. He-he.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="bar_arena_manager_game_3">
        <text>I've got some thing in a gasmask. They call it a snork. On the outside - skinny and frail, but really fucking athletic.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_arena_manager_game_31">
        <text>Gimme that snork of yours.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_arena_manager_game_32">
        <text>No, I won't fight a snork.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_arena_manager_game_321">
        <text>You scared of being beaten by some weirdo in a gasmask?</text>
    </string>
	<string id="bar_arena_manager_game_4">
        <text>You're lucky. We just caught a young bloodsucker. He's kinda dumb, but he's got all the bad traits of an adult one.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_arena_manager_game_41">
        <text>Gimme that sucker.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_arena_manager_game_42">
        <text>Nah I don't want to fight a bloodsucker.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_arena_manager_game_421">
        <text>Yeah, that's what I thought.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="bar_arena_manager_game_5">
        <text>We've got a dwarf in a hood - a burer.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_arena_manager_game_51">
        <text>Gimme that thing.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_arena_manager_game_52">
        <text>Nah, I won't fight a burer.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_arena_manager_game_521">
        <text>He barely reaches your crotch, and you're scared of him?</text>
    </string>
	<string id="bar_arena_manager_game_6">
        <text>This is a special case. I don't know where they caught this one, but they just call him "Beast".</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_arena_manager_game_61">
        <text>Give me that Beast of yours.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_arena_manager_game_62">
        <text>Nah, that sounds too scary even for me.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_arena_manager_game_621">
        <text>I'm scared of him too, but I'm not the one who fights on the Arena. So who's the real wuss?</text>
    </string>
	<string id="bar_arena_manager_game_100">
        <text>Payment to take part in a fight - 1000 rubles.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_arena_manager_game_101">
        <text>Here.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_arena_manager_game_105">
        <text>I don't have any cash.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_arena_manager_game_1051">
        <text>And you again without any money...</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_arena_manager_game_110">
        <text>2000 rubles for participation.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_arena_manager_game_111">
        <text>Here.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_arena_manager_game_115">
        <text>No cash, sorry.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_arena_manager_game_1151">
        <text>Go away then.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_arena_manager_game_120">
        <text>3000 rubles and the bloodsucker's yours.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_arena_manager_game_121">
        <text>Here.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_arena_manager_game_125">
        <text>I'm empty, sorry.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_arena_manager_game_1251">
        <text>Don't joke, even my little son has that much cash.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_arena_manager_game_130">
        <text>Not so fast. First, pay 5000 rubles for participation.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_arena_manager_game_131">
        <text>Here's the money.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_arena_manager_game_135">
        <text>I don't have any money.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_arena_manager_game_1351">
        <text>I've got a beggar, too.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_arena_manager_game_140">
        <text>If I agree, pay 5,000 for participation.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_arena_manager_game_141">
        <text>Here's 5000 rubles.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_arena_manager_game_145">
        <text>I don't have any money.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_arena_manager_game_1451">
        <text>Even stalkers, and they're beggars. Lived to see it.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="bar_arena_manager_game_200">
        <text>Good morning. (Chuckles) One more thing. Bet on the time it takes you to kill the monster. If you succeed, you win, if not, you lose. The less time you choose, the bigger the winnings.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_arena_manager_game_201">
        <text>Ten seconds, double win.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_arena_manager_game_202">
        <text>30 seconds, you win half the bet.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_arena_manager_game_203">
        <text>One minute, you win a fifth of the bet.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_arena_manager_game_204">
        <text>I changed my mind.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_arena_manager_game_2041">
        <text>Ugh, you rag. I'm not giving you your money back anyway.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="bar_arena_manager_game_300">
		<text>The official part is over. Please enter the waiting room.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_arena_manager_info_0">
        <text>I have a couple of questions.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_arena_manager_info_1">
        <text>Go ahead, ask.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_arena_manager_info_10">
        <text>No more questions.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_arena_manager_info_11">
        <text>What kind of place is this?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_arena_manager_info_111">
        <text>This is my business here. The arena is a place where any stalker can test his strength in a duel with mutants. And if a stalker shows enough skill, he can earn money. A year and a half ago, I cleaned up a nest of bloodsuckers with a friend. We drove the last one into a house, all the exits were blocked, we sit and wait. Here my friend says: "I bet I'll put him down alone in two minutes." I walked into the house and put him to bed. That's how the idea came about. Duty let us make an arena out of the hangar. Now we have our own business in the Zone.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_arena_manager_info_12">
        <text>Why are there live mutants here?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_arena_manager_info_121">
        <text>It's a deal with Duty. They used to kill everything during their raids, and then I offered them money in exchange for the wounded mutants. We agreed quickly. Since then, I have had an almost inexhaustible source of living mutants. I even sell the bodies outside the Zone. They are very popular.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_arena_manager_info_13">
        <text>Where are you from?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_arena_manager_info_131">
        <text>Where am I from? I've been all over. I don't know what to think of as my homeland anymore. I spent a long time in Africa, then a few years in Ecuador. And then I heard about this wonderful place and realized that you can earn good money here.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="bar_arena_manager_rules_0">
        <text>What are the rules?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_arena_manager_rules_1">
        <text>Oh, the rules are very simple. I invented them myself. There is a cell, and a mutant is launched into it. You pay the money, and you also choose the time in which you kill the monster. If you make it, you win. If you don't make it, I keep the money. If you die, I promise to bury you with all the honors. The less time you choose, the bigger the winnings.</text> <!-- end of unused arena stuff -->
    </string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barman_ecolog_flash_done_0">
		<text>Here is the flash drive professor Kruglov gave me.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barman_ecolog_flash_done_21">
		<text>Good boy. I think Duty will be very grateful for this info. Here is your reward.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barman_ecolog_flash_done_31">
		<text>Well, well. Information? Straight from professor Kruglov? You taking the piss or what? "I am professor Kruglov and I am deleting reports about our research for the sake of science and humanity..." And this is the info you were supposed to get!? Well, shit...I'm sure Duty will be "happy" about this.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barman_ecolog_flash_done_41">
        <text>Well, well. Information? Straight from professor Kruglov? È îäíîâðåìåííî ó âñåõ àíàðõèñòîâ Ñâîáîäû â ðàäèóñå 10 êèëîìåòðîâ??? What, do you take me for an idiot? Well, shit...I'm sure Duty will be "happy" about this.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barman_killer_ambush_0">
		<text>I accomplished my mission. Here is Tyran's PDA.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barman_killer_ambush_1">
		<text>Wow, Messer! Great job! What can I say? You made me happy, man. I wasn't sure you'd manage, to be honest...but you're alive and they're not!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barman_killer_ambush_2">
		<text>What about my reward?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barman_killer_ambush_3">
		<text>Here. Your reward as promised.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barman_veterans_finish_0">
		<text>Here is Lucky's PDA. I did what you asked.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barman_veterans_finish_1">
		<text>Nice, Messer. Great job! What can I say? You made me happy, man. I wasn't sure you'd manage, to be honest...but you're alive and they're not!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barman_veterans_finish_11">
		<text>What about the reward?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barman_veterans_finish_111">
		<text>You're a hero, man, a real hero. Here, that should make you happy.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barman_deserter_finish_0">
		<text>I fulfilled your assignment.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barman_deserter_finish_1">
		<text>And here's the reward.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barmen_jobs_0">
        <text>Do you have work for me?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_bar_barmen_jobs_1">
        <text>No, nothing today.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_bar_barmen_jobs_2">
        <text>There is work, but only for veterans.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_bar_barmen_jobs_21">
        <text>More to the point. What do you need me to do?</text>
    </string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barmen_jobs_22">
        <text>Sorry, I can't do this right now.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_bar_barmen_jobs_211">
        <text>In the "Wild territory", anarchists shot down the helicopter with the scientists. The survivors, including Professor Kruglov, are surrounded. Whether or not the Freedom fighters will attack the scientists is unknown. Kruglov was carrying very important information. We need that information at any cost, and it cannot fall into the hands of the anarchists.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_bar_barmen_jobs_2111">
        <text>Is that all?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_bar_barmen_jobs_21111">
        <text>You have until tonight, because then the mutants will come out, and you don't want to be in Wild Territory after dark. Duty promises me good pay for this, so I'll pay you nicely. Just don't let the anarchists retrieve information and deliver it to me.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_bar_barmen_jobs_211111">
        <text>Well, I agree. I hope the information is worth it.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_bar_barmen_jobs_2111111">
        <text>Done. As soon as the information is mine, you'll get your reward.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_bar_barmen_jobs_211112">
        <text>No. Let Duty and Freedom sort themselves out. Dragging me into it helps nobody.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_bar_barmen_jobs_2111121">
        <text>As you wish.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_bar_barmen_jobs_212">
        <text>There is a serious matter. In the "Wild territory" there's a group of veterans causing problems for anyone trying to pass through the area. To cut a long story short, they have some kind of deal with Duty, but this was made before they began starting trouble. The point here is that Duty can't break their agreement, but these guys are too impudent. Duty needs them removed. The job is challenging, but pays well.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_bar_barmen_jobs_2121">
        <text>Anything else? It's strange that Duty wouldn't take care of this themselves.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_bar_barmen_jobs_21211">
        <text>Duty cares about its reputation, so they want to be considerate. You have to destroy the leader, nicknamed "Lucky" and bring his PDA as evidence.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_bar_barmen_jobs_212111">
        <text>Fine. I hope that I will not regret it.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_bar_barmen_jobs_2121111">
        <text>Great solution, and I think, pity there's nothing.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_bar_barmen_jobs_212112">
        <text>No, I won't do this right now.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_bar_barmen_jobs_2121121">
        <text>It's your call. Just remember that this is a good chance to gain favor with Duty.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_bar_barmen_jobs_3">
        <text>Don't rush it. The scientists haven't yet	figured it out, and are already eager to do something else.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barmen_jobs_4">
        <text>Kill the soldier</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_bar_barmen_jobs_41">
        <text>Keep going.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barmen_jobs_411">
        <text>I need you to get rid of one grunt.. and don't ask who he is, just do it. Well? Can I rely on you?</text>
    </string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barmen_jobs_4111">
        <text>I'll take it.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barmen_jobs_4112">
        <text>Another time.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barmen_start_1111">
		<text>Let's start. You ready?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barmen_start_1131">
		<text>Hey, stalker.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barmen_start_121">
		<text>My guys caught a crazy Stalker near the Radar. Now he's in my office. Hurry!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barmen_start_1211">
		<text>Let's go.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barmen_start_1212">
		<text>No.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barmen_start_12121">
		<text>Damn it! Here I am, busting my arse while you're off wandering in the woods! Go get those damn documents or we won't make any progress!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barmen_start_121211">
		<text>OK.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barmen_start_131">
		<text>Well, Messer, now we just need to deal with the's a Scorcher and open the way North! You ready to go now?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barmen_start_1312">
		<text>Yes.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barmen_start_13121">
		<text>OK, Messer, you've got the protective prototype so you'll be safe from the emissions. I have the bunker coordinates. Don't forget that the prototype won't protect you forever, so you need to get to the bunker ASAP and turn off the's a Scorcher. I don't know what will happen after that but I am sure it will be worth it. The only thing we can be sure of is that the road to the Zone's center will be open.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barmen_start_1313">
		<text>Go on.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barmen_start_1314">
		<text>All we need to do is get to the antennas and disable them. Got it?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barmen_start_1315">
		<text>Got it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barmen_start_1316">
		<text>Oh yeah, one last thing! The leader of Duty, I marked him on the map, needs a volunteer to carry out some sort of assignment at the military warehouses. If you're interested, you can drop by. I'll talk with the guards, they'll let you in.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barmen_start_132">
		<text>No, I'm not ready yet.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barmen_start_1321">
		<text>Get ready, Messer! This task can't wait.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barmen_start_141">
		<text>Bullseye, go smoke yet, I will come in half an hour. I paper with "Medpribor" read.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barmen_start_1511">
		<text>Here we can talk.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barmen_start_1512">
		<text>Maybe he knows something about the "burner" of the brain. It would be necessary to question him.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barmen_start_15121">
		<text>I'll try.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barmen_start_1513">
		<text>How's it going?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barmen_start_15131">
		<text>We need a scientific first aid kit.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barmen_start_151311">
		<text>Here, I have.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barmen_start_1513111">
		<text>Great!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barmen_start_161">
		<text>What do you want, Messer?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barmen_start_162">
		<text>Hey Messer! Times change but you don't still grumpy and aloof. Here, take a seat, have a drink - might make you nicer...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barmen_start_171">
		<text>So, Messer, how are things coming along?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barmen_start_172">
		<text>I'm back, job done.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barmen_start_1721">
		<text>Wait, wait, wait. Go into the room, there's too many people.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barmen_start_17211">
		<text>Well, let's go.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barmen_start_1712">
		<text>Well, let's see what you got.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barmen_start_17121">
		<text>I brought the folder from the lab, here.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barmen_start_171211">
		<text>Good job, but the most important thing is that you survived. So, let's see... the report about the experiments, some theoretical background, diagrams, graphs... Damn, damn I can not understand. Nothing, we'll get to the riddle's answer. Here, I have something for you as compensation.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barmen_start_1712111">
		<text>What now?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barmen_start_17121111">
		<text>Now I have half an hour to get through it all. Come over later and talk.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barmen_start_171211111">
		<text>Well.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barmen_start_181">
		<text>What do you want, Messer?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barmen_start_182">
		<text>Hey Messer! Times change but you don't still grumpy and aloof. Here, take a seat, have a drink - might make you nicer...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barmen_start_191">
		<text>I'm here with documents yet understand. Like what?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barmen_start_2">
		<text>Hey Messer! Have you brought the documents from the Institute?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barmen_start_21">
		<text>No, I haven't got the docs from the Institute yet.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barmen_start_211">
		<text>That ain't good, Messer, ain't good at all... You understand how much we need 'em, don'tcha? We need 'em bad, believe me. The Brain's a Scorcher is right under our noses but we don't even know what it is! Go get the documents right now - we'll talk after that.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barmen_start_2111">
		<text>I think I understand.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barmen_start_22">
		<text>Here are the documents from the Institute.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barmen_start_221">
		<text>Great work, Messer! We have the documents at last. It seems that in such cases you can rely on. Come back often I still have a couple of interesting things.\n So... I need to have a look at them now and maybe I'll work out how to get North. While I do that, if you have problems with money, you can fight at the Arena. The owner of the Arena is Arni, I've uploaded his coordinates.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barmen_start_2211">
		<text>OK.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barmen_start_22111">
		<text>Now listen up!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barmen_start_231">
		<text>It's still early, I transcripts is not yet understood.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barmen_start_3">
		<text>What do you want, Messer?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barmen_start_4">
		<text>Hi, Tagged. Time is running out and you don't change, still the same unsociable. Sit down have a drink, maybe a bit kinder.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barmen_start_201">
		<text>There's an errand. But here I do not wish to speak. Too noisy, and too much of ears a lot. If you are interested, come talk to me in private. It is associated with those pieces of paper with "Medpribor".</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barmen_start_2011">
		<text>I'm interested in serious things, let alone discuss.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barmen_start_20111">
		<text>Go to my room. Garik you will miss.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barmen_start_201111">
		<text>Went.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barmen_start_2012">
		<text>No, now is not interested.</text>
	</string>
    <string id="bar_bar_barmen_jobs_room_0">
        <text>What is the job?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_bar_barmen_jobs_room_1">
        <text>Stalkers for several years interested in the opening of the passage to the North, to the center. But while the passage is closed, and those who go there, never come back. There is information about a "brain burner" that blocks the way to the North, but what it is nobody knows. For those documents that you brought with "Medpribor", something begins to dawn. It seems that the "brain burner" artificial nature, but the data is not enough to say. The documents referred to a laboratory X-18, who also worked on this project. Descriptions converge with abandoned underground premises in the Dark valley, known as the "Dark laboratory".</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_bar_barmen_jobs_room_11">
        <text>Want I went to the "Dark lab"? And what is the payment?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_bar_barmen_jobs_room_111">
        <text>Hehe. The Stalker knows his stuff, huh? Business is business, but the swag does not pull his pocket. Hehe. So, listen, you need a good procitati the lab. When the Area boomed, time to evacuate, no one was. Certainly a lot of things there. If you get a folder with documents about the "antennas" or "emitters" I'll pay you well. In addition, the award will share information about the "burner." However, the laboratory is closed, and to open it, you will need two electronic keys. I'll give you one, of course, if you agree to go there, and the second will take a Hog in the Dark valley. Well, so what?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_bar_barmen_jobs_room_1111">
        <text>Well, taken.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_bar_barmen_jobs_room_11111">
        <text>The job is dangerous, without question. What is happening there now, is unknown. And besides, the Dark valley has always been an unsafe place. So, be careful out there. All you need to do is get a second key to lab X-18, to penetrate it and get the missing part of the documents. Don't forget to get a suit that protects from radiation. Without it, you will not pass. Information about the stash of costume can buy from a local informant.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_bar_barmen_jobs_room_111111">
        <text>Something does not leave me feeling that you're not the first Stalker to death to send. OK, I'll try to find the file.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_bar_barmen_jobs_room_1112">
        <text>No, I don't want to take on.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_bar_barmen_jobs_room_11121">
        <text>Your business, Labeled. Just know, while this is the only clue that can help us to solve a "brain burner" and open the road to the North. Sooner or later someone will have to do it.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barmen_jobs_room_2">
        <text>That's what, Bullseye, I can't deal with these fucking drawings.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_bar_barmen_jobs_room_21">
        <text>What do we do?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_bar_barmen_jobs_room_211">
        <text>I hope you agree to bring these folders to the scientists. Deciphering the documents, we will not just get information about any research, we get the description of the "burner" and will find a way how to deal with it. Agree, it should be interesting.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_bar_barmen_jobs_room_2111">
        <text>Well, I agree.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_bar_barmen_jobs_room_21111">
        <text>All righty then, just be quick with it. Time is money... and life.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_bar_barmen_jobs_room_2112">
        <text>I'm sorry, but I'm not interested in it now.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_bar_barmen_jobs_room_21121">
        <text>Well, see for yourself. Folder yet I keep. If you change your mind, you know where to go.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barmen_jobs_room_3">
        <text>At the time you came, Labeled. I make out that the scientists gave, and that's what I'll tell you: "brain Burner" is a great size antenna, maybe even one, the radiation of which ruin people packs. But not so simple. Radiation this is not a continuous stream, and waves. That is, you can podgadat moment when this radiation is minimal, to get inside and disable the "antenna" through the main office.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_bar_barmen_jobs_room_31">
        <text>Keep going.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_bar_barmen_jobs_room_311">
        <text>In General, all we need is to shut her the fuck up. If you agree, then I will send you information about the peaks and downs of radiation. The coordinates of the bunker I know. In addition, only you have "hat - nevidimka", and without it in any downturn will not make their way. But don't forget that the prototype will not be able indefinitely to protect you from radiation. You must get into the bunker beneath the antennas and disable the "burner." Beyond that, I don't know, but I feel it was worth it. I do know one thing: the road to the center of the Zone will be open. So, come from?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_bar_barmen_jobs_room_3111">
        <text>Taken. Oh, where we did not disappear!?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_bar_barmen_jobs_room_31111">
        <text>Here's all the necessary information. Good luck to you, Labeled. And... take care of yourself.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_bar_barmen_jobs_room_3112">
        <text>No, stop, I'm already soon a psychopath for hire will.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_bar_barmen_jobs_room_31121">
        <text>Then you have 40 years to wait for "the Scorch" the batteries sit down. And maybe more. You're a Soviet military development remember - they can work for decades, completely broken, with no half of parts.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barmen_talk_info_0">
		<text>I want to know something.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barmen_talk_info_1">
		<text>What is it?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barmen_talk_info_10">
		<text>Thank you.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barmen_talk_info_3">
		<text>What do you know about Strelok?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barmen_talk_info_31">
		<text>An experienced stalker as far as I know. He used to "work" through the northern exits from the Zone. He was hardly ever seen here but there are rumours that he took his group right into the center of the Zone.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barmen_talk_info_4">
		<text>What is this place?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barmen_talk_info_41">
		<text>This is a village were workers used to live - workers that got employed by the facilities near the lake. There's rumors going around that some of them are still in working condition.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barmen_talk_info_5">
        <text>What do you know about the Doctor?</text>
    </string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barmen_talk_info_51">
		<text>He's an old stalker in retirement. He lives in the marshes. Nobody really knows how to get there. He used to be in Strelok's group back in the day.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barmen_talk_info_6">
		<text>What do you know about a stalker called Journalist?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barmen_talk_info_61">
		<text>There was a man that went by that name, but I haven't seen him for a long time. A month, to be exact. And that's a lot of time in the Zone. He was interested in many documents. I dunno anything more.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barmen_talk_info_7">
		<text>Tell me about the mobile science labs.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barmen_talk_info_71">
		<text>As you probably know by now, some government organisations are studying the "nature" of the Zone. Rumors say, that them and their experiments caused the Zone itself to appear. Strelok and his crew tried to find out more about the Zone, but he and his entire crew disappeared. I don't know the truth, I only can guess. Government organisations put mobile laboratories around the Zone, isolated metallic bunkers protected by stalkers. These bunkers are self sufficient and able to work for a couple of months on their own. We keep in touch with one of these bunkers at Yantar. The eggheads are pretty okay guys, they'll share some info, and we help them in times of need. Works for both of us.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barmen_talk_info_8">
		<text>What is the wish granter?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barmen_talk_info_81">
		<text>Oh! That's an interesting question... I wish I knew the answer. I can tell you the legend about the Granter if you want but you make up your own mind how much truth there's in it. Wanna hear it?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barmen_talk_info_811">
		<text>Well, that's very interesting.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barmen_talk_info_8111">
		<text>This legend is about the Monolith, which may be what caused the Zone to appear. When the Zone exploded in 2006, they evacuated people living near it and the Zone itself was cordoned off by the Army. Everyone was panicking, nobody knew what was going on, the Zone was expanding and the field labs couldn't do anything! Loads of people died there. Everyone was afraid of the radiation which could affect half of Europe. After a few years had passed, some reckless guys like you appeared. They called themselves stalkers. They started to sneak past army cordons believing that there are things in the Zone that would make them rich. Bit by bit, they brought out weird things, artifacts and which eventually turned out a race for them. Scientists went after them like crazy. They paid fantastic money for just one trinket back then, not like now.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barmen_talk_info_81111">
		<text>Go on...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barmen_talk_info_811111">
		<text>After a while, the first tales and legends about what's deep inside the Zone by the tumbledown nuclear power plant started to circulate. It was also then that one of the veterans told us the story of Monolith that allegedly grants your wishes. You should have seen the hysteria: experienced, level-headed men started trying to break through to the center - everyone wanted something from the Monolith. We got some morbid details about the first stalker who made it through to the Monolith...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barmen_talk_info_8111111">
		<text>Go on... tell me more.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barmen_talk_info_81111111">
		<text>When the Zone had just appeared many people were trapped inside and cut off from the outside world. Most of them died pretty quickly but there were a few lucky survivors who tried to do something about it. One of these survivors found himself by the station and noticed some strange light inside. With no way back he decided to try to get closer. He saw the broken roof of the sarcophagus and the light coming out through it. He climbed up the wall and looked inside. Among the debris of metal and molten concrete there lay a massive black rock. It was the Monolith. The stalker managed to shake off the "spell" and realised that he had climbed very close to the sarcophagus, which was highly radioactive. He was scared to death but through the fear he could sense the Monolith calling to him. The Monolith called to him and he came to see strange, unbelievable things about the Monolith inside his head...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barmen_talk_info_811111111">
		<text>Cool...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barmen_talk_info_811111112">
		<text>I don't know what's true in this story and what's not but the point is the guy made a wish which came true, while the Zone grew by 5 kilometers. It seems the Zone gobbles up more land for every wish that is granted... But that ain't gonna stop hotshots like you. They keep trying to break through with their precious little wishes in their hearts...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barmen_talk_info_812">
		<text>I'm interested in some information.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barmen_talk_info_8121">
		<text>Alright then. What are you interested in?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barmen_jobs_room_darklabdoc_done_0">
		<text>I brought the docs from the lab, here.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barmen_jobs_room_darklabdoc_done_1">
		<text>That's my boy, good job. It's great to have you alive. Alright, let's take a look... something about experiments, some calculations, some scientific babble, grams... Crap, I don't understand any of this. But don't worry, we'll find the answer soon. Here, you can consider this your reward.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barmen_jobs_room_darklabdoc_done_11">
		<text>What now?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barmen_jobs_room_darklabdoc_done_111">
		<text>I need at least half an hour to read all of this. Come later, we'll talk.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barmen_jobs_room_darklabdoc_done_1111">
		<text>OK.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barmen_jobs_room_complete_0">
        <text>I'm back. The job is done.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_bar_barmen_jobs_room_complete_1">
        <text>Wait, wait. Let's go to my room. Too many people here.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_bar_barmen_jobs_room_complete_11">
        <text>Ok, let's go.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barmen_jobs_room_decoding_done_0">
        <text>Here it is, the work of the greatest minds of the eastern block! Here, hold this.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_bar_barmen_jobs_room_decoding_done_1">
        <text>Are you joking? Wait, i need to decode these papers, read all of it and think about it. You did a great job. I feel like it will help us a lot in defeating the Scorcher. Come here after half an hour.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_bar_barmen_jobs_room_decoding_done_11">
        <text>OK.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_bar_drunk_dolg_quest_finish_0">
        <text>I took care of the sniper, here's his PDA.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_bar_drunk_dolg_quest_finish_1">
        <text>Oh, damn. Thank you friend, you saved my ass. I owe you one. Here, for you, new generation detector. You see, life is a long play and without help you won't get a happy ending. You help me, I help you, we won't die together.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_bar_drunk_dolg_quest_finish_11">
        <text>Just remember to not be drunk when I need your help.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_bar_drunk_dolg_quest_start_0">
        <text>What ya need?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_bar_drunk_dolg_quest_start_1">
        <text>What I need? Hm... You need to kill one son of a bitch! A sniper recently popped up here, he comes out at night and starts shooting people. He's smart, he can tell when someone's out to get him. He instantly runs away, leaving no traces behind. He appears around the water tower, I sent you his spot to your PDA. I can't do this on my own. I'm a Dutyer, so Freedom will quickly take care of my ass if I try to do anything. Help me.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_bar_drunk_dolg_quest_start_11">
        <text>I'll try.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_bar_drunk_dolg_quest_start_111">
        <text>Thank you. You'll get me the documents of that sucker, and I will give you this detector. I swear on my life! But you... eh, nevermind, no unnecessary questions. Don't forget: the sniper appears at midnight and dissapears when the first rays of the sun begin to shine.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_bar_drunk_dolg_quest_start_12">
        <text>Nah, I don't want to take care of this right now.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_bar_drunk_dolg_quest_start_121">
        <text>Crap. What am I supposed to do? Nobody wants to help me.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="bar_bar_drunk_dolg_start_11">
		<text>Our goal - elimination of mutants. Especially zombies. Hic!... You can join our ranks. But first you need to prove your dedication to the clan.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_drunk_dolg_start_111">
		<text>I understand.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_drunk_dolg_start_21">
		<text>What's up? Any news? You haven't whacked the little piece of shit, I can see it in your eyes. Life sucks... Listen, at least have a drink with me, will you, friend?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_drunk_dolg_start_31">
		<text>What's up man? Any news?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_drunk_dolg_start_41">
		<text>Hic... you helped, yes. Come here, let's drink for Duty, eh? Eh!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_hunter_quest_finish_0">
		<text>I found it. Here is your rifle.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_hunter_quest_finish_1">
		<text>Thanks. I'm so grateful! You really helped me out there, you really did. Goddamn. Here take this - it ain't much but it's all I got. I won't forget your help and I hope to repay you in time. Now I'm gonna shoot all of these mutant bastards, that's for sure.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_hunter_quest_start_0">
		<text>Go on.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_hunter_quest_start_1">
		<text>I'll give you anything! Just return my rifle, I beg you. Be careful though. Those zombies aren't the friendly kind.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_hunter_quest_start_11">
		<text>OK, I'll try.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_hunter_quest_start_111">
		<text>I won't cheat you.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_hunter_quest_start_1111">
		<text>OK.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_hunter_quest_start_12">
		<text>No. I've got more important things to do.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_hunter_quest_start_121">
		<text>Up to you... but I hope you change your mind.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_hunter_quest_start_1212">
		<text>We'll see.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_hunter_start_11">
		<text>I've got a big problem man! I... I lost my rifle. I wanted to shoot some bloodsuckers but I barely got away. Damn! Listen, bro... if you get it back I'll pay you. I've grown used to it, it's like an extension of my arm now... It's here near the Bar, by the Rostok factory. In one of the houses. When I was getting out through a window, I had to drop it along with my backpack...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_hunter_start_21">
		<text>Hey! Any news? Did you find it?!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_hunter_start_31">
		<text>Thanks bro'! I'll never forget that you helped me!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_deadcity_map_0">
		<text>Are you not interested in the map of Shining Path?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_deadcity_map_1">
		<text>For 10000 rubles.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_deadcity_map_11">
		<text>Here's your map.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_deadcity_map_12">
		<text>Maybe another time.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_reward_0">
		<text>Wolfhound said you've got something for me.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_reward_1">
		<text>Sure. Here is a grenade launcher for helping him with Kruglov, and 1000 cash on top. I'll give you some useful info for free to sweeten the deal too.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_reward_2">
		<text>Thank you.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_reward_3">
		<text>Here's what I got to say. You helped Freedom and made the right choice. Your fate is now tied with that of Freedom, and Duty has you in its sights. I'd say you oughtta go to the abandoned military base and join the ranks of Freedom - they need good fighters. There will be shootouts between the groups soon and whoever chooses the right side won't regret it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_start_11">
		<text>I work as a dealer of information. I sell important info, and I can tell you some interesting rumors. My information is valuable and very useful to the one who possesses it!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_start_21">
		<text>Hello, Messer. You helped Freedom and made the right choice. Your fate is now tied with that of Freedom and Duty has you in its sights. I'd suggest you go to the abandoned military base and join Freedom - they need good fighters.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_start_211">
		<text>I'll think about it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_start_2111">
		<text>So Messer, what brings you here? Wanna buy some info or are you selling today?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_talk_0">
		<text>So you're connected with Freedom then?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_talk_1">
		<text>I can't answer that question right now. All I can say is that I am not a member of any group.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_talk_about_freedom_0">
		<text>Tell me about the Freedom faction.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_talk_about_freedom_1">
		<text>Sure, no problem! Freedom is one of the oldest groups in the Zone and the only one that openly opposes government troops and research teams. Its founders are dead - they were killed during a big bloodbath after the army dropped a large assault force in the Zone but the ability to control the Zone from outside was destroyed at the same time. There is some evidence to suggest that the first Zone was used as a secret army weapons' testing site . If that's true, they must have used some powerful shit.Anyway, what was I saying...? Oh yeah, Freedom is the only group that is trying to stop the government from gaining control over the testing site again. God knows what will happen if they start testing their shit again, so Freedom is trying to hold out at all costs.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_talk_about_freedom_2">
		<text>Åñëè "Ñâîáîäà" õî÷åò óäåðæàòü âîåííûé ïîëèãîí â ñâîèõ ðóêàõ, then what about Duty?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_talk_about_freedom_3">
		<text>Duty is basically controlled from the outside by the government. Their current objective is to clear the territory of mutants and destroy Freedom, which is what they are doing at the moment. When the time is right, they will drop a large assault force in the Zone and take control of the area.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_talk_about_freedom_4">
		<text>Man, that sounds scary. Thanks for the information.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_trade_info_0">
		<text>I want to buy some information.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_trade_info_21">
		<text>Right now, I can sell you information about Strelok's group virtually for nothing - 400 roubles.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_trade_info_211">
		<text>OK, I'll take it. Here's 400.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_trade_info_2111">
		<text>It's located by the MedPribor Research Institute, there's a stash in the underground. It probably contains information about the group's plans and a list of group members.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_trade_info_212">
		<text>No, I changed my mind.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_trade_info_2121">
		<text>Up to you. Come to the bar when you decide otherwise - I'm always here.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_trade_info_31">
		<text>Right now, I have some information about a group that made it to the center of the Zone. I'm practically giving it away - only 200 roubles.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_trade_info_311">
		<text>OK, I'll buy it. Here's 200.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_trade_info_3111">
		<text>Strelok along with his group got to the center of the Zone. What they found there is unknown, one thing  we do know is that Strelok disappeared. I've heard that the Journalist knows what's up with him.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_trade_info_312">
		<text>No, I changed my mind.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_trade_info_3121">
		<text>Up to you. Come to the bar when you decide otherwise - I'm always here.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_trade_info_41">
		<text>I've got some information about the secret of Lake Yantar. The price is just 350 roubles - any less and I'd be paying you!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_trade_info_411">
		<text>Okay, I'll buy. Take 350.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_trade_info_4111">
		<text>The secret of Lake Yantar is similar to the secret of the Brain Scorcher and their effects are similar in many ways. Some kind of emission zombifies all who come in contact with it. The zombified stalkers move around the center of some emitter, attacking everyone. There is information to suggest that the solution to the riddle of Lake Yantar is in the lower levels of the Dark Laboratory. Here are the coordinates of the emitter at Lake Yantar and those of the Brain Scorcher. As a bonus, I'll give you the coordinates to the Dark Laboratory.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_trade_info_412">
		<text>No, I changed my mind.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_trade_info_4121">
		<text>Up to you. Come to the bar when you decide otherwise - I'm always here.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_trade_info_999">
		<text>I have no new information right now.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_trade_info_outfit_0">
		<text>I want to buy info about the stash with armor and stuff.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_trade_info_outfit_1">
		<text>2000 rubles.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_trade_info_outfit_11">
		<text>Take it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_trade_info_outfit_111">
		<text>The armor stash is located at the Garbage, in a small forest where wild dogs live.\nHere are the coordinates.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_trade_bio_0">
		<text>I need information about people. Bios, contacts, connections and all that.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_trade_bio_1">
		<text>Currently I have info about these people:</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_trade_bio_100">
		<text>Toad</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_trade_bio_1001">
		<text>Toad's biography costs 3000 rubles.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_trade_bio_101">
		<text>Wolf</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_trade_bio_1011">
		<text>Wolf's costs 1000.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_trade_bio_102">
		<text>Fanatic</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_trade_bio_1021">
		<text>Fanatic's costs 1000.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_trade_bio_103">
		<text>Fox</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_trade_bio_1031">
		<text>Fox's costs 1000.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_trade_bio_104">
		<text>Tolik</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_trade_bio_1041">
		<text>Tolik's biography will cost you 1000 rubles.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_trade_bio_105">
		<text>Nimble</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_trade_bio_1051">
		<text>Nimble's biography will cost you 1000 rubles.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_trade_bio_106">
		<text>Petruha</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_trade_bio_1061">
		<text>Petruha's biography will cost you 1000 rubles.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_trade_bio_107">
		<text>Major Kuznetsov</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_trade_bio_1071">
		<text>Biography of Major Kuznetsov will cost you 1000 rubles.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_trade_bio_108">
		<text>Lieutenant Chuguykin</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_trade_bio_1081">
		<text>Biography of Lieutenant Chuguykin will cost you 1000 rubles.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_trade_bio_109">
		<text>Guide</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_trade_bio_1091">
		<text>Guide's biography will cost you 3,000 rubles.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_trade_bio_110">
		<text>Seriy</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_trade_bio_1101">
		<text>Seriy's biography will cost you 1000 rubles.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_trade_bio_111">
		<text>Yurik</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_trade_bio_1111">
		<text>Yurik's biography will cost you 1000 rubles.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_trade_bio_112">
		<text>Bes</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_trade_bio_1121">
		<text>Bes' biography will cost you 1000 rubles.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_trade_bio_113">
		<text>Vasya Boar</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_trade_bio_1131">
		<text>Vasya Boar's will cost you 1000 rubles.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_trade_bio_114">
		<text>Prapor</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_trade_bio_1141">
		<text>Prapor's biography will cost you 1000 rubles.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_trade_bio_115">
		<text>Mole</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_trade_bio_1151">
		<text>Mole's biography will cost you 1000 rubles.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_trade_bio_116">
		<text>Pied Piper</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_trade_bio_1161">
		<text>Pied Piper's biography will cost you 3,000 rubles.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_trade_bio_117">
		<text>Captain Maksimenko</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_trade_bio_1171">
		<text>Captain Maksimenko's biography will cost you 1000 rubles.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_trade_bio_118">
		<text>Doctor</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_trade_bio_1181">
		<text>Doctor's biography costs 1000 rubles.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_trade_bio_119">
		<text>Borov</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_trade_bio_1191">
		<text>Borov's biography will cost you 1000 rubles.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_trade_bio_120">
		<text>Shaggy Sergei</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_trade_bio_1201">
		<text>Shaggy Sergei's biography will cost you 1000 rubles.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_trade_bio_121">
		<text>Bullet</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_trade_bio_1211">
		<text>Bullet's biography will cost you 1000 rubles.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_trade_bio_122">
		<text>Zheka Doublet</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_trade_bio_1221">
		<text>Biography of Zheka Doublet will cost you 1000 rubles.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_trade_bio_123">
		<text>Kalugin P. I.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_trade_bio_1231">
		<text>Biography of Kalugin P. I. will cost you 1000 rubles.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_trade_bio_124">
		<text>Barkeep</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_trade_bio_1241">
		<text>Barkeep's biography will cost you 3,000 rubles.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_trade_bio_125">
		<text>Garik</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_trade_bio_1251">
		<text>Garik's biography will cost you 1000 rubles.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_trade_bio_126">
		<text>Zhorik</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_trade_bio_1261">
		<text>Zhorik's biography will cost you 1000 rubles.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_trade_bio_127">
		<text>Snitch</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_trade_bio_1271">
		<text>Snitch's biography will cost you 1000 rubles.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_trade_bio_128">
		<text>Hunter</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_trade_bio_1281">
		<text>Hunter's biography will cost you 3,000 rubles.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_trade_bio_129">
		<text>Brome</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_trade_bio_1291">
		<text>Brome's biography will cost you 1000 rubles.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_trade_bio_130">
		<text>Baldy</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_trade_bio_1301">
		<text>Baldy's biography will cost you 1000 rubles.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_trade_bio_131">
		<text>Spotty</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_trade_bio_1311">
		<text>Spotty's biography will cost you 1000 rubles.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_trade_bio_132">
		<text>Arnie</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_trade_bio_1321">
		<text>Arnie's biography will cost you 1000 rubles.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_trade_bio_133">
		<text>Lelik</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_trade_bio_1331">
		<text>Lelik's biography will cost you 1000 rubles.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_trade_bio_134">
		<text>Beast</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_trade_bio_1341">
		<text>Beast's biography will cost you 1000 rubles.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_trade_bio_135">
		<text>General Voronin</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_trade_bio_1351">
		<text>Biography of General Voronin will cost you 1000 rubles.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_trade_bio_136">
		<text>Colonel Petrenko</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_trade_bio_1361">
		<text>Biography of Colonel Petrenko will cost you 1000 rubles.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_trade_bio_137">
		<text>Captain Ivantsov</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_trade_bio_1371">
		<text>Captain Ivantsov will cost you 1000 rubles.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_trade_bio_138">
		<text>Sergeant Plichko</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_trade_bio_1381">
		<text>Biography of Sergeant Plichko will cost you 1000 rubles.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_trade_bio_139">
		<text>Sergeant Kitsenko</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_trade_bio_1391">
		<text>Biography of Sergeant Kitsenko will cost you 1000 rubles.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_trade_bio_140">
		<text>Professor Kruglov</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_trade_bio_1401">
		<text>Biography of Professor Kruglov will cost you 1000 rubles.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_trade_bio_141">
		<text>Wolfhound</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_trade_bio_1411">
		<text>Wolfhound's biography will cost you 1000 rubles.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_trade_bio_142">
		<text>Tyrant</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_trade_bio_1421">
		<text>Tyrant's biography will cost you 1000 rubles.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_trade_bio_143">
		<text>Lucky</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_trade_bio_1431">
		<text>Lucky's biography will cost you 1000 rubles.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_trade_bio_144">
		<text>Freeman</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_trade_bio_1441">
		<text>Freeman's biography will cost you 1000 rubles.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_trade_bio_145">
		<text>Screw</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_trade_bio_1451">
		<text>Screw's biography will cost you 1000 rubles.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_trade_bio_146">
		<text>Pavlik</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_trade_bio_1461">
		<text>Pavlik's biography will cost you 1000 rubles.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_trade_bio_147">
		<text>Lukash</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_trade_bio_1471">
		<text>Lukash's will cost you 1000 rubles.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_trade_bio_148">
		<text>Skinflint</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_trade_bio_1481">
		<text>Skinflint's biography will cost you 1000 rubles.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_trade_bio_149">
		<text>Max</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_trade_bio_1491">
		<text>Max's biography will cost you $ 1000.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_trade_bio_150">
		<text>Chef</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_trade_bio_1501">
		<text>Chef's biography will cost you 1000 rubles.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_trade_bio_151">
		<text>Cap</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_trade_bio_1511">
		<text>Cap's biography will cost you 1000 rubles.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_trade_bio_152">
		<text>Murk</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_trade_bio_1521">
		<text>Murk's biography will cost you 1000 rubles.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_trade_bio_153">
		<text>Kolyan</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_trade_bio_1531">
		<text>Kolyan's biography will cost you 1000 rubles.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_trade_bio_154">
		<text>Tolyan</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_trade_bio_1541">
		<text>Tolyan's biography will cost you 1000 rubles.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_trade_bio_155">
		<text>Skull</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_trade_bio_1551">
		<text>Skull's biography will cost you 1000 rubles.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_trade_bio_156">
		<text>Ara</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_trade_bio_1561">
		<text>Ara's biography will cost you 1000 rubles.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_trade_bio_157">
		<text>Insane Stalker from the Freedom Faction</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_trade_bio_1571">
		<text>Biography of the insane stalker will cost you 1000 rubles.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_trade_bio_158">
		<text>Sakharov</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_trade_bio_1581">
		<text>Sakharov's biography will cost you 1000 rubles.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_trade_bio_159">
		<text>Semenov</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_trade_bio_1591">
		<text>Semenov's biography will cost you 1000 rubles.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_trade_bio_160">
		<text>Vasiliev</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_trade_bio_1601">
		<text>Vasiliev's biography will cost you 1000 rubles.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_trade_bio_161">
		<text>Ghost</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_trade_bio_1611">
		<text>Ghost's biography will cost you 1000 rubles.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_trade_bio_162">
		<text>Oleg "Fiend" Gusarov</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_trade_bio_1621">
		<text>Oleg "Fiend" Gusarov's biography will cost you 3,000 rubles.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_trade_bio_163">
		<text>Leshiy</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_trade_bio_1631">
		<text>Leshiy's biography will cost you 3,000 rubles.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_trade_bio_164">
		<text>Scarecrow</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_trade_bio_1641">
		<text>Scarecrow's biography will cost you 3,000 rubles.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_trade_bio_165">
		<text>Vampire</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_trade_bio_1651">
		<text>Vampire's biography will cost you 3,000 rubles.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_trade_bio_166">
		<text>Father Diodor</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_trade_bio_1661">
		<text>Father Diodor's biography will cost you 3,000 rubles.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_trade_bio_167">
		<text>Goiter</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_trade_bio_1671">
		<text>Goiter's biography will cost you 3,000 rubles.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_trade_bio_168">
		<text>Clumsy</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_trade_bio_1681">
		<text>Clumsy's biography will cost you 3,000 rubles.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_trade_bio_169">
		<text>Poker</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_trade_bio_1691">
		<text>Poker's biography will cost you 3,000 rubles.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_trade_bio_170">
		<text>Barin</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_trade_bio_1701">
		<text>Barin's biography will cost you 3,000 rubles.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_trade_bio_171">
		<text>Sparrow</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_trade_bio_1711">
		<text>Sparrow's biography will cost you 3,000 rubles.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_trade_bio_172">
		<text>Master</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_trade_bio_1721">
		<text>Master's biography will cost you 3,000 rubles.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_trade_bio_173">
		<text>Prapor</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_trade_bio_1731">
		<text>Prapor's biography will cost you 3,000 rubles.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_trade_bio_174">
		<text>Twig</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_trade_bio_1741">
		<text>Twig's biography will cost you 3,000 rubles.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_trade_bio_175">
		<text>Smartass</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_trade_bio_1751">
		<text>Smartass' biography will cost you 3,000 rubles.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_trade_bio_176">
		<text>Friar</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_trade_bio_1761">
		<text>Friar's biography will cost you 3,000 rubles.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_trade_bio_177">
		<text>Polkan</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_trade_bio_1771">
		<text>Polkan's biography will cost you 3,000 rubles.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_trade_bio_178">
		<text>Lyokha Jaw</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_trade_bio_1781">
		<text>Lyokha's biography will cost you 1000 rubles.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_trade_bio_179">
		<text>Charon</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_trade_bio_1791">
		<text>Charon's biography will cost you 1000 rubles.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_trade_bio_180">
		<text>Sasha White</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_trade_bio_1801">
		<text>Sasha's biography will cost you 1000 rubles.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_trade_bio_181">
		<text>Vasily Petrovich</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_trade_bio_1811">
		<text>Vasily's biography will cost you 1000 rubles.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_trade_bio_182">
		<text>Dushman</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_trade_bio_1821">
		<text>Dushman's biography will cost you 1000 rubles.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_trade_bio_183">
		<text>Greyhound</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_trade_bio_1831">
		<text>Greyhound's biography will cost you 1000 rubles.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_trade_bio_2">
		<text>New information is available.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_trade_bio_10011">
		<text>Here is the money.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_trade_bio_10012">
		<text>No, some other time.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_pda_reward_0">
		<text>I want to sell a PDA.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_pda_reward_1">
		<text>What PDAs do you want me to sell?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_pda_reward_11">
		<text>Duty PDA.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_pda_reward_12">
		<text>Freedom PDA.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_pda_reward_13">
		<text>Lyokha Jaw's PDA.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_pda_reward_14">
		<text>Mercenary Leader's PDA.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_pda_reward_141">
		<text>I'll give you 500 rubles for the Merc leader's PDA.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_pda_reward_15">
		<text>Vasily Petrovich's PDA.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_pda_reward_111">
		<text>For each I will give you no more than 150 rubles.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_pda_reward_1111">
		<text>I agree.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_pda_reward_1112">
		<text>No, that's not right.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_trade_dlg_doc_0">
		<text>Are you interested in documents from the Mercs?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_trade_dlg_doc_1">
		<text>For 1000 rubles.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_trade_dlg_doc_11">
		<text>Here.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_trade_dlg_doc_12">
		<text>No, I changed my mind.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_trade_killer_doc_0">
		<text>Are you interested in documents from the Mercs?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_trade_killer_doc_1">
		<text>For 1500 rubles.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_trade_killer_doc_11">
		<text>Here.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_trade_killer_doc_12">
		<text>No, I changed my mind.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_visitors_1_start_11">
		<text>...it's about time someone whacked Borov! If I knew who it was, I'd buy him a drink.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_visitors_1_start_111">
		<text>Yeah, it was about time.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_visitors_1_start_21">
		<text>...someone really pissed off Freedom: I heard one of their groups was destroyed in the Wild Territory...I wonder who did it?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_visitors_1_start_211">
		<text>Yeah, I wish I knew...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_visitors_1_start_31">
		<text>...finally someone had the balls to clear out the bloodsuckers in the Wild Territory... What was Duty doing all this time?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_visitors_1_start_311">
		<text>What was Duty doing? They were doing Freedom, what else?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_visitors_1_start_41">
		<text>...I heard someone whacked the leader of Freedom. They're in for some tough times I think. Duty is gonna really put a squeeze on 'em...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_visitors_1_start_411">
		<text>Let's hope so.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_visitors_1_start_51">
		<text>So you wiped out those veterans? Well done, friend! Six stalkers went missing in that area recently...we all suspected those mad veterans. It's a good thing that they've been dealt with.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_visitors_1_start_511">
		<text>Yeah, many people wanted those veterans to "leave".</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_visitors_1_start_61">
		<text>You turned off the emissions at Yantar? Wow...you're a lucky nut, damn it, I'm glad that someone finally managed to deal with that thing! You can't imagine how many of our boys died there... but now the scientists will work out what it was. We might even be able to deal with the Scorcher now...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_visitors_1_start_611">
		<text>I want to believe that the Scorcher can be switched off.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_visitors_1_start_71">
		<text>What do you want? Don't you see, I'm trying to relax here...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_visitors_1_start_711">
		<text>What's new?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_visitors_1_start_7111">
		<text>I hear Strelok came back. He's got all the equipment you need to get to the Machine... He's hiding now though 'cause a lot of people are after him. Some are open about it while others are trying to keep their interest a in secret. Rumour has it even Duty and Freedom have joined the hunt... each with their own agenda.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_visitors_1_start_71111">
		<text>Looks like Strelok is right to hide.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_visitors_10_start_71">
		<text>What do you want?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_visitors_10_start_711">
		<text>Can you tell me anything that would be useful to a rookie?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_visitors_10_start_7111">
		<text>Useful to a rookie? Well, listen up. To the North, not far from the Brain Scorcher, Freedom have set up their HQ in an old military base. They're notorious nihilists, anarchists and criminals - freedom fighters, freaking guerrillas all of them. All they do is sabotage research groups, attack army units and constantly skirmish with Duty. These skirmishes are now spilling over into a small-scale war for survival. Let me give you some advice: never get involved with them. They'll only accept you if you're totally crazy and there's a reward on your head. Ha-ha-ha. Can you believe that?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_visitors_10_start_71111">
		<text>Thanks for your advice.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_visitors_12_start_71">
		<text>What do you want?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_visitors_12_start_711">
		<text>Can you tell me anything that would be useful to a rookie?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_visitors_12_start_7111">
		<text>Well, there used to be this group led by Strelok. There were all sorts of legends about it going around the Zone...good and bad, but few people really knew the truth. The truth is that they wanted to deal with the Zone, find out what created it. That's why military stalkers were after them but they didn't know where to look. The government didn't want normal stalkers to know things they shouldn't have known. One day Strelok found something really important and made a move towards the center of the Zone with some of his boys. Half of the group died on the way but the rest made it through... What happened to them there - no one knows. Looks like they've copped it. The other group members were caught and killed off... I don't think there are any of them left now. Sad story, eh?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_visitors_12_start_71111">
		<text>Yeah... looks like someone really doesn't want the Zone to be understood...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_visitors_13_start_71">
		<text>What do you want?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_visitors_13_start_711">
		<text>Can you tell me anything that would be useful to a rookie?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_visitors_13_start_7111">
		<text>Mercs are kinda like Freedom, only worse. At least Freedom have some ideals, but these dogs, they'll do anything for money. Someone really needs to kill 'em all before they drag something really dangerous out of the Zone into the normal world! They're based in Shining Path and there's a sniper in every tall building, understand? They're not keen on strangers.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_visitors_13_start_71111">
		<text>I see. Looks like you have to be careful in Shining Path.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_visitors_14_start_71">
		<text>What do you want?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_visitors_14_start_711">
		<text>Can you tell me anything that would be useful to a rookie?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_visitors_14_start_7111">
		<text>If you haven't been in the Arena, I'd recommend it - it's a good way to make money and show everyone what you can do. Not everyone has the balls to fight the next monster and that's a pity! Man, as soon as I save up enough cash for decent armor, I'm there.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_visitors_14_start_81">
		<text>What do you want?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_visitors_14_start_82">
		<text>Are you Baldy? I need to talk to you.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_visitors_14_start_83">
		<text>Suppose I am. What do you want?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_visitors_14_start_84">
		<text>Spotty got saved from the Radar, but Hunchback is dead.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_visitors_14_start_85">
		<text>Dammit!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_visitors_14_start_86">
		<text>Spotty is in bad shape, his brain doesn't work anymore. Maybe you can talk to him? We need to find out the Scorcher's schedule.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_visitors_14_start_87">
		<text>No! Don't ask me to do this. Hunchback is dead 'cause of me and what happened to Spotty is my fault too. I left them, betrayed them, deserted them and ran away! I can't look Spotty in the eyes after what I did!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_visitors_14_start_88">
		<text>C'mon, chill man. Tell me what happened.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_visitors_14_start_89">
		<text>The three of us were getting ready to try to get through to the North. We didn't know when the Scorcher emissions were lower but Spotty managed to get the info somewhere...I don't know where... We were half-way through the sector, when the Scorcher suddenly switched on again. Spotty passed out straight away and fell down the hillside. I panicked and said that we should leave everything and go back. Hunchback managed to pull himself together and said that we had to get Spotty out... I said "You're an idiot, don't you wanna live? It's over for him, how are we gonna carry him all the way back?" Just as he managed to convince me and started to climb down to get Spotty... another wave came. By the time I came to my senses I was by the military base... I thought Hunchback and Spotty stayed there... but Hunchback got him out and didn't make it himself... he got him out...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_visitors_14_start_90">
		<text>OK, Baldy, OK. Calm down, man. Thanks for telling me what happened. I'll talk to Spotty myself.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_visitors_14_start_91">
		<text>Sorry. I'm not in the mood for talking... I'd rather just have another drink.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_visitors_2_start_71">
		<text>What do you want?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_visitors_2_start_711">
		<text>What's new?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_visitors_2_start_7111">
		<text>There was a guy... He had a lisp and walked with a stoop so he got the name Hunchback. He was a bit crazy...talked to himself and to animals... but apart from that, he was alright. He disappeared a long time ago in the center with Strelok... they say Strelok is back now.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_visitors_2_start_71111">
		<text>I wonder where he is now.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_visitors_3_start_71">
		<text>What do you want?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_visitors_3_start_711">
		<text>What can you tell me?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_visitors_3_start_7111">
		<text>The Rostok factory is infested with bloodsuckers now! They come out at night. I heard there's something really important at the factory that's nearby, something essential to someone. Duty sent some guys in there recently but they all died and their screams were heard kilometers away.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_visitors_3_start_71111">
		<text>Thanks for the information.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_visitors_4_start_71">
		<text>What do you want?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_visitors_4_start_711">
		<text>What did you hear?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_visitors_4_start_7111">
		<text>If you go around Lake Yantar you'll come to the scientists' camp - they're do research of some sort there... They were dropped in by helicopter and they get regular supplies too. They've got a nice spot there really... You can deal with them too - they buy artifacts and might even give you a job to do.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_visitors_4_start_71111">
		<text>Thanks for the information.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_visitors_5_start_71">
		<text>What do you want?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_visitors_5_start_711">
		<text>What did you hear?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_visitors_5_start_7111">
		<text>Nobody has managed to get through the vehicle scrapyard because of the Brain Scorcher. Some people did see a stalker go through the invisible border, fall over, then get up in a couple of minutes and head straight for the center of the scrapyards. He ain't been seen since...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_visitors_5_start_71111">
		<text>Interesting...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_visitors_6_start_71">
		<text>What do you want?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_visitors_6_start_711">
		<text>What did you hear?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_visitors_6_start_7111">
		<text>Missing stalkers come back from time to time. It's a scary sight, I tell you: they mumble something and reach for their weapons, which they lost somewhere... One came to a Duty outpost some time ago and a crowd gathered to look at him. Someone even recognized him... He was scary...red eyes, all bloodshot and bruised...couldn't say a word, just moaned like an animal and went around in circles. Duty took him in, but he died after a couple of days anyway. Something happens to people in the Zone, but what is it?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_visitors_6_start_71111">
		<text>I'd like to know too.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_visitors_7_start_71">
		<text>What do you want?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_visitors_7_start_711">
		<text>What did you hear?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_visitors_7_start_7111">
		<text>There are a lot of zombies around Lake Yantar. They wander around and attack any human they see. If you're spotted you might wanna run for your life - there are too many of them former stalkers around there... They died at the lake and that's all that's left of 'em.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_visitors_7_start_71111">
		<text>Yeah, I wouldn't want to join them.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_visitors_8_start_71">
		<text>What do you want?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_visitors_8_start_711">
		<text>What did you hear?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_visitors_8_start_7111">
		<text>Traders say that there's a real treasure trove of artifacts in the center of the Zone, so anyone who makes it through will make enough money for two lifetimes. Personally, I think there's more to this. Obviously the traders think about their own interests, but there are strange rumours going around. Apparently, there's something better than artifacts there - something that ain't from this world, something alien or from another dimension altogether! They call it the Wish-granting machine. I heard a legend about a stalker who made it through. Only every time someone makes a wish the Zone grows and nobody who gets there uses his wish to make it disappear. I guess when you get to the Machine you don't give a shit about anyone else.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_visitors_8_start_71111">
		<text>That's sad.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_visitors_9_start_71">
		<text>What do you want?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_visitors_9_start_711">
		<text>What did you hear?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_visitors_9_start_7111">
		<text>Everyone who believes in the Monolith is completely nuts. They keep banging on about it but nobody actually knows what's in the center of the Zone. An invisible crystal that fell from the skies...ha-ha-ha! I reckon one of the secret labs blew up - I mean some stalkers used to work in a few of them. But, obviously, you can't bomb the Zone. Not only will the radiation spread all over the world, half of Europe would be flattened by the Zone's reaction. "Someone" has gone totally mad lately - I heard they're killing normal stalkers for no reason at all. How do you like that? Damn fanatics.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_visitors_9_start_71111">
		<text>I think it deserves some attention.</text>
	</string>


;ãîâíîïåðåâîä
	<string id="bar_dolg_base_guard_acces_0">
		<text>Why don't you let strangers?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_base_guard_acces_1">
		<text>Heh... where did you came from, so naive? We have a war, you know? With the bandits of Freedom. Regular skirmishes around gunmen on "Wild territory".</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_base_guard_acces_11">
		<text>The war with the Freedom faction? Why?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_base_guard_acces_111">
		<text>Because the bandits of Freedom has no place in the Area, they must be destroyed. If you are interested, then ask the Barkeep, he'll explain everything, but I'm too busy for this.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_base_guard_acces_12">
		<text>And if I want to go into Duty? What should I do?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_base_guard_acces_121">
		<text>Pay fee is 10 000 rubles, and will receive a pass. With him go to the administrator of the Duty, he to you will appoint validation.</text>
	</string>
    	<string id="bar_dolg_base_guard_acces_1211">
        <text>Well, here's the money.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_base_guard_acces_12111">
		<text>That's great, take the admission, and run with it to the administrator Petrenko, I noted on the map. And again, don't do it in the bunker to go until you receive a pass from Ivantsova.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_base_guard_acces_1212">
		<text>No, I changed my mind.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_base_guard_acces_12121">
		<text>Well, it's your business, take care.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_base_guard_acces_13">
		<text>Thank you.</text>
	</string>


	<string id="bar_dolg_base_guard_acces_14">
        <text>I need to see your boss.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_base_guard_acces_141">
        <text>Why?</text>
    </string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_base_guard_acces_1411">
        <text>I have some very useful information.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_base_guard_acces_14111">
        <text>Alright, go talk  to the Captain. He will tell how useful that information is.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_base_guard_acces_14112">
        <text>What is that information?</text>
    </string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_base_guard_acces_141121">
        <text>Map of Shining Path. It should interest you.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_base_guard_acces_1411211">
        <text>Alright, you can go. The leadership is in the  bunker.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_base_guard_rules_0">
		<text>Barkeep told me that your leadership has some sort of assignment for me.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_base_guard_rules_1">
		<text>Yes, he let us know about you, but before we let you in I want to brief you on our rules. So listen, our rules are simple. First rule - it's forbidden to shoot on our territory. If you break the rule twice, our patrol will open fire on you. Even if you make a run for it, you won't appear on our territory again - our guards will make sure of that. If you act calmly, you won't have any problems.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_base_guard_rules_2">
		<text>Got it. Anything else?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_base_guard_rules_3">
		<text>Yes, that's enough. You can pass.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_base_guard_rules_4">
		<text>Got it. Anything else?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_base_guard_rules_5">
		<text>That's about it. If you want to try to join Duty, feel free. We need good men but I'm warning you: before being accepted, you'll have to do a few dangerous jobs. We don't need pussies so everyone is tested.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_base_guard_start_11">
		<text>Halt! Outsiders aren't allowed in the Duty base!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_base_guard_start_21">
		<text>What are you standing there for? Keep moving.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_base_guard_start_31">
		<text>Go on, bro. Remember: Duty's mission is to cleanse.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_base_guard_talk_0">
		<text>Why don't you let outsiders in?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_base_guard_talk_1">
		<text>Where did you naive boys come from? There's a war going on, right? We’re fighting Freedom bandits! We have regular skirmishes with their fighters in the Wild Territory.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_base_guard_talk_2">
		<text>A war with Freedom? Why?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_base_guard_talk_3">
		<text>Because there is no place for those Freedom bandits in the Zone - they must be destroyed. If you're interested, go ask the Barkeep to explain everything. I'm busy.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_guard_bunker_start_11">
		<text>Halt! Only members can go in there! We can't let you inside the bunker without a special pass. If you want to get one go see Colonel Petrenko. He's in the administration area across the yard.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_guard_bunker_start_111">
		<text>Why don't you let me into the bunker?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_guard_bunker_start_1111">
		<text>A pass... If we want to go, you should get special pass. Go to Petrenko, he'll explain everything.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_guard_bunker_start_21">
		<text>What are you standing there for? Keep moving.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_guard_bunker_start_31">
		<text>Go on. Remember: Duty's mission is to cleanse.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_ivancov_join_0">
		<text>I want to join the Duty faction.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_dolg_ivancov_join_1">
		<text>Go to Petrenko, he'll explain everything.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_dolg_ivancov_join_11">
		<text>Where is he?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_dolg_ivancov_join_111">
		<text>Inside the administration building, through the courtyard from here.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_ivancov_start_11">
		<text>What do you want?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_ivancov_start_21">
		<text>I'm listening.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_ivancov_start_31">
		<text>Hello, friend.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_ivancov_deadcity_map_0">
		<text>I need to meet with your leader.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_ivancov_deadcity_map_1">
		<text>What for?</text>
    </string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_ivancov_deadcity_map_11">
        <text>I have a map of Dead City. I think you'd be interested in it.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_ivancov_deadcity_map_111">
        <text>A map of Dead City, you say? Um... Well, let's see... Come in, he's in his bunker.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_ivancov_test_start_0">
        <text>Colonel Petrenko sent me to you. Here is the permission.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_dolg_ivancov_test_start_1">
        <text>Hmm. Hmm. Hmm. So, you say Duty has another optimist volunteer, huh?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_dolg_ivancov_test_start_11">
        <text>Something like that.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_dolg_ivancov_test_start_111">
        <text>We'll see, we'll see. But before you draw conclusions, I need you to pass a small test. You need to get the archive folder from the abandoned building across the street. The task is easy; just go inside, take the folder and bring it to me. What can be easier, right? When I have the folder, then we will decide whether you are suitable for Duty or not.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_dolg_ivancov_test_start_1111">
        <text>Okay, I'll be right back.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_dolg_ivancov_test_start_1112">
        <text>This seems too easy... I don't like it. Maybe some other time.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_ivancov_test_finish_0">
        <text>I've completed your mission. Here's the archive folder.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_dolg_ivancov_test_finish_1">
        <text>Excellent. Let's assume you've passed the test. Keep the access to the bunker. Now go to General Voronin, only he can induct you into the group.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_dolg_ivancov_test_finish_11">
		<text>Thank you.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_leader_job_0">
		<text>What can I do for Duty?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_leader_job_1">
		<text>That's a good question Messer, and there's an equally good answer to it: kill Freedom anarchists. You'll get a reward for every PDA of theirs you bring and you might get promoted too. Take all the PDAs you get to Colonel Petrenko - he gives out the rewards. Bring our fighters' PDAs to him, too, so that the information doesn't fall into the wrong hands.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="bar_dolg_leader_join_0">
		<text>I want to join the Duty faction.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_leader_join_1">
		<text>A laudable desire. Colonel Petrenko and captain Ivantsov already reported about you. Before accepting you, there is one thing I need you to do.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_leader_join_11">
		<text>What's that?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_leader_join_111">
		<text>You see, something... Now we keep territorial fighting with a Freedom faction, and we do not have enough weapons more powerful than we have. In Freedom, there are several excellent RG-6 grenade launchers. If you managed to retrieve one for us, then I would gladly accept such a brave stalker into our group. Since you're not one of us, you can gain their trust, and then steal an RG-6 from under their noses. Well, what do you think?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_leader_join_1111">
		<text>I accept.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_leader_join_11111">
		<text>Excellent. I've uploaded the coordinates of their base in the Army Warehouses. And another tip - we have information that one of their cooks, known simply as "Chef", knows where they are and has a loose tongue. He is a drunk, so bring some vodka with you.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_leader_join_1112">
		<text>No, I'm not ready for such an undertaking.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_leader_join_11121">
		<text>It's your call.</text>
	</string>


	<string id="bar_dolg_leader_prisyaga_0">
		<text>I am ready to swear the oath.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_leader_prisyaga_1">
		<text>Good man! Repeat after me: "I, a stalker known as Messer, swear to defend the goals and ideals of Duty."</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_leader_prisyaga_2">
		<text>I, a stalker known as Messer, swear to defend the goals and ideals of Duty.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_leader_prisyaga_3">
		<text>To protect the Earth from the dangers of the Zone, to seek out and destroy anything it spawns within and beyond its borders.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_leader_prisyaga_4">
		<text>To protect the Earth from the dangers of the Zone, to seek out and destroy anything it spawns within and beyond its borders.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_leader_prisyaga_5">
		<text>To fight any nonconformists, be they individual stalkers or groups.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_leader_prisyaga_6">
		<text>To fight any nonconformists, be they individual stalkers or groups.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_leader_prisyaga_7">
		<text>And to give my life in the name of justice and order on Earth!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_leader_prisyaga_8">
		<text>And to give my life in the name of justice and order on Earth!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_leader_prisyaga_9">
		<text>Congratulations! You are now a full-fledged member of Duty.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_leader_quest_rg6_finish_0">
		<text>I completed the mission. I brought the RG-6.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_leader_quest_rg6_finish_1">
		<text>Good job. This is what we exactly needed.\nMesser, you passed the test. You are now accepted into our clan. From now on, you are a regular private of Duty. I will get some missions for you. For each of them completed, you will be rewarded and perhaps even promoted.\nTo officially become a part of our faction, you also need to swear our oath.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_leader_quest_borov_finish_0">
        <text>I've fulfilled my mission; Borov is dead and I've brought the information.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_dolg_leader_quest_borov_finish_1">
        <text>Excellent work, Marked One. You did what three of our agents were unable to do. You are a good fighter and I am glad that you are with us. For your services to Duty, I promote you to the rank of Veteran. Report to Petrenko for a well deserved reward.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_leader_quest_svoboda_ambush_finish_0">
        <text>I've fulfilled my mission; the Mercenary ambush was destroyed, the leader was killed, and I brought his PDA.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_dolg_leader_quest_svoboda_ambush_finish_1">
        <text>You've done a phenomenal job. All of our fighters can learn from you. I promote you to the rank of Keeper of Duty. Go to Petrenko, he will give you a reward.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_leader_quest_svoboda_leader_finish_0">
        <text>I've fulfilled my mission. The Freedom leader is dead, and I've brought his belongings.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_dolg_leader_quest_svoboda_leader_finish_1">
        <text>I am nearly in disbelief. You've destroyed the head of the anarchists. This will lead to a rapid disintegration of the group. The war is not yet over, but the outcome is already a foregone conclusion. I promote you to the rank of Master of Duty. Wear this title with honor. Petrenko will provide you with a suitable reward.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_leader_quest_start_0">
		<text>What are my current tasks?</text>
    </string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_leader_quest_start_1">
        <text>Your task is to go to the Dark Valley, eliminate Borov, and locate all information you can about Lab X18. \n Recently, Borov's men took my scout, who carried important information about the X18 laboratory. He has probably been killed. Now, we are not ready for a large-scale war with the bandits, so your goal is Borov and the information. Find him, kill him, then get me the information about the X18 lab.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_leader_quest_start_2">
        <text>You must destroy the Mercenaries in the Wild Territory, where they've settled and have been wreaking havoc. Destroying the leader, known as Tyrant, should be enough to cause the group to disperse. Tyrant was previously a highly ranked member of Freedom; he is a known psychopath and sadist. As soon as he is destroyed, the detachment will not be so dangerous and, most likely, will retreat. Bring me Tyrant's PDA as proof that he has been dealt with. And be careful, they are known to ambush their victims.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_leader_quest_start_3">
        <text>The war with Freedom is coming to an end. You've helped our cause, but now I want to put an end to this war once and for all. I'm sending you to assassinate the leader of Freedom.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_leader_quest_start_4">
		<text>No new tasks available for now.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_leader_start_11">
		<text>I'm listening.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_leader_start_21">
		<text>What brings you here, brother?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_leader_start_31">
		<text>You brought the RG-6?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_leader_start_311">
		<text>Yes, here is the RG-6.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_leader_start_3111">
		<text>Good work, stalker. This is exactly what we need. Well, Messer, you carried out my request, and in return you can take this suit. I think you'll like it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_leader_start_41">
		<text>What brought you to me, brother?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_leader_start_51">
		<text>The war with Freedom is coming to an end, Messer. You played your part in fighting for the cause and now I want to finish this war. I want you to kill the Freedom leader.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_leader_start_81">
		<text>What brings you to me, brother? You destroyed the Freedom anarchist leader, which led to the disintegration of the group. The war is not over yet, but its outcome is already predetermined. Your merit is great, and we will not forget it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_leader_deadcity_map_0">
		<text>A map of Dead City isn't interesting?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_leader_deadcity_map_1">
		<text>I'll give you 20,000 rubles for it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_leader_deadcity_map_11">
		<text>Okay, great! Here's the map.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_leader_deadcity_map_111">
		<text>Here's the money. How did you manage to get it?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_leader_deadcity_map_1111">
		<text>It's a long story.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_leader_deadcity_map_12">
		<text>Okay, thank you.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_leader_deadcity_map_121">
		<text>Wait, you have a map?!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_leader_deadcity_map_1211">
		<text>No, I was just wondering if I should look for it or not.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_leader_deadcity_map_12111">
		<text>Well, if you find it, come.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_leader_deadcity_map_2">
		<text>Did you find the map?! Marked One, give it to me! Here, these 20,000 rubles are yours. You did a great job. How did you manage to get it?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_leader_deadcity_map_21">
		<text>It's a long story.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_newbie_start_11">
		<text>Hello, stalker. Join Duty! We need good fighters! I only joined recently and look at the cool uniform they gave me!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_newbie_start_21">
		<text>Hello, Messer. I'm glad you're with us. Duty is really going to need good fighters soon.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_novice_start_2">
		<text>Hey, fellow stalker.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_novice_start_3">
		<text>Tell me about Duty.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_novice_start_31">
		<text>We've been here since the beginning. The first group was made up of the surviving members of special units sent into the Zone to find out what caused it to appear. We found ourselves in pretty dire circumstances. After half of the unit died horribly, those who survived swore that they wouldn't leave here until they understood what is going on in the Zone..  until they defeat it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_novice_start_4">
		<text>Tell me about Freedom.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_novice_start_41">
		<text>They're thugs who don't understand that the Zone is an ulcer on Earth's body. They want to spread it all over the world, a piece in every household. They'll do anything to achieve that goal and I can't wait to put an end to it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_novice_start_5">
		<text>You want to defeat the Zone?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_novice_start_51">
		<text>Yes and we manage to a large degree. During the cleaning operations, whole swarms of mutants on the way to the Zone's center are destroyed.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_novice_start_6">
		<text>Thank you.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_petrenko_join_0">
        <text>I'd like to join the ranks of Duty.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_dolg_petrenko_join_1">
        <text>Why?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_dolg_petrenko_join_11">
        <text>I want to fight the zone.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_dolg_petrenko_join_111">
        <text>Hmm... You seem like an  experienced fighter.  I  personally believe that you can join our ranks, but you will need to prove yourself to the captain. Here's the pass. You should go to him now.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_dolg_petrenko_join_1111">
        <text>Thank you.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_dolg_petrenko_join_112">
        <text>Piss off, Messer. We don't need thugs like you in our ranks!</text>
    </string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_petrenko_start_11">
		<text>Greetings stalker. Want to trade? We can do that. Want a job? We can give you a job...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_petrenko_start_21">
		<text>How can I help?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_petrenko_start_31">
		<text>Hello brother! What brings you to me?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_veteran_start_2">
		<text>What do you want?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_zastava_11">
		<text>Go on, keep moving. What are you staring at?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_zastava_21">
		<text>Hey man! I'm glad you haven't been eaten by mutants yet.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_zastava_about_zastava_0">
		<text>There was a massacre by the outpost. What happened?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_zastava_about_zastava_1">
		<text>That's the last wave of mutants that came before the blowout. It's quiet for three or four days and then there's another wave. If not for us, there'd be no Bar, there'd be no Duty; we're the last barrier in the way of these crazy mutants. A lot of our boys met their end here.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_zastava_talk_0">
		<text>I'd like to know something.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_zastava_talk_1">
		<text>What do you want to know?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_zastava_talk_2">
		<text>It's my first time here. Could you tell me a little about this place?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_zastava_talk_21">
		<text>Before the accident in '86 this was an industrial area. As you can see, there ain't much left of it now... In the basement by the hangar you'll find the 100 Rads bar. The place is run by the local trader who doubles up as a barman. If you want to trade, talk, get a mission or find out the latest news, that's the place to go. There's also the Arena where you can fight and make some cash. Duty's base is not far from the Arena. If you want to join Duty go straight over there - they'll tell you who to speak to. Oh, by the way, all of this area is protected by Duty so behave and keep your weapons holstered. If you start shooting, the patrol will "calm you down" pretty quickly.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_zastava_talk_211">
		<text>You said there's a bar here. Can you tell me where exactly it is?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_zastava_talk_2111">
		<text>In the basement behind the hangar...I'll mark it on your map.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_zastava_talk_21111">
		<text>Thanks for the information.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_zastava_talk_212">
		<text>You said the Duty base is here. How do I get to it?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_zastava_talk_2121">
		<text>It's not far from the Arena. I've marked it on the map for you.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_zastava_talk_21211">
		<text>Thanks for the information.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_zastava_talk_213">
		<text>You said there's an Arena here? Where exactly is it?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_zastava_talk_2131">
		<text>Go out of the hangar with the broken roof and you'll end up right in front of it. I'll mark it on your map.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_zastava_talk_21311">
		<text>Thanks for the information.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_zastava_talk_214">
		<text>Thanks for the information.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_zavskald_reward_0">
		<text>I'm here on business.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_zavskald_reward_1">
		<text>I take it you want something from me.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_zavskald_reward_11">
		<text>I shot down a pig on my way here. They say it's a valuable one.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_zavskald_reward_111">
		<text>I heard you shot Borov. You deserve to get some cash and a decent gun for that. Do your new weapon justice!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_zavskald_reward_1111">
		<text>Don't you worry about that.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_zavskald_reward_12">
		<text>I had a little "chat" with Tyran. Basically, he understood his mistake and promised to behave in the future. I'm pretty sure he won't be breaking his word - the dead don't lie.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_zavskald_reward_121">
		<text>Tyran was a real pain in the ass for us! I'm glad you terminated him. Here is your reward - an S14 Thunder, our trademark weapon.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_zavskald_reward_1211">
		<text>Not bad. I'm off to do more of the same. See you.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_zavskald_reward_13">
		<text>Didn't Voronin tell you anything?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_zavskald_reward_131">
		<text>Wow, congratulations! It's quite an achievement to kill Freedom's leader. Man, I wish I was as tough as you.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_zavskald_reward_1311">
		<text>Drink a lot of milk, train, and listen to your mother. Thanks for the new gear. I'm gonna go now.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_zavskald_reward_14">
		<text>Here, another PDA delivery.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_zavskald_reward_141">
		<text>Good work.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_zavskald_reward_1411">
		<text>Thanks.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_psih_start_pain_11">
		<text>There's something in my head... Agh... What's going on... I don't understand...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_psih_start_pain_21">
		<text>Uhuh... and to think.... aaah....</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_psih_start_pain_31">
		<text>My head... It's full... It's full of shit... ahh....</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_psih_start_pain_41">
		<text>No.... why... I don't want it... I don't want it to...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_psih_start_pain_51">
		<text>No, it won't do it to me! It won't do it to me!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_psih_start_pain_61">
		<text>I'm okay! I'm okay... I can push through this...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_psih_start_pain_71">
		<text>I can do this!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_psih_start_pain_81">
		<text>...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_psih_start_pain_91">
		<text>Good luck to you, Baldy.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_psih_talk_pain_0">
		<text>Spotty, can you hear me?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_psih_talk_pain_1">
		<text>No.... Why... I don't want it... I don't want it to...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_psih_talk_pain_11">
		<text>Can you hear me?!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_psih_talk_pain_111">
		<text>No! It won't do it to me! Not to me!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_psih_talk_pain_1111">
		<text>Speak to me!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_psih_talk_pain_11111">
		<text>My head... It's full... It's full of shit... ahh....</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_psih_talk_pain_111111">
		<text>Waste of time! I need a scientific medkit...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_psih_talk_pain_1111111">
		<text>There's something in my head... Agh... What's going on... I don't understand...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_psih_talk_pain_11111111">
		<text>Here, take this medkit!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_psih_talk_pain_111111111">
		<text>I'm normal, I'm normal... I can do this!...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_psih_talk_pain_11111112">
		<text>Shit! I don't have a medkit... Need to ask Barkeep for one...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_psih_talk_pain_111111121">
		<text>My head... Voices in my head... They're talking to me...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_psih_give_medkit_0">
		<text>Here, take this medkit! It should help!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_psih_give_medkit_1">
		<text>Gaah... My head... hurts...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_psih_talk_gorbun_0">
		<text>How are you feeling? Can you talk?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_psih_talk_gorbun_1">
		<text>My vision is doubling...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_psih_talk_gorbun_11">
		<text>So it helped... What do you know bout the Scorcher? When is the radiation at its weakest?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_psih_talk_gorbun_111">
		<text>Radiation... Screw it! Hunchback! Hunchback is dead!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_psih_talk_gorbun_1111">
		<text>Who the hell is Hunchback?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_psih_talk_gorbun_11111">
		<text>A stalker... We went together to the Scorcher... Hunchback, Baldy and I...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_psih_talk_gorbun_111111">
		<text>Baldy? Baldy was with you?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_psih_talk_gorbun_1111111">
		<text>Yes... Baldy... The one with the VSK-94...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_psih_talk_gorbun_11111111">
		<text>That's the guy in the bar! I gotta talk to him...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_psih_talk_lisiy_0">
		<text>I talked to Baldy. He said you have some info about the Scorcher.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_psih_talk_lisiy_1">
		<text>Yes... I do... It cost me quite a lot... and it wasn't completely true...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_psih_talk_lisiy_11">
		<text>Tell me everything ya know.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_psih_talk_lisiy_111">
		<text>I don't remember much... The radiation drops down sometimes... sometimes around the morning... sometimes around the high noon... It usually drops for an hour... sometimes more... Gahh... It's you...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_psih_talk_lisiy_1111">
		<text>What?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_psih_talk_lisiy_11111">
		<text>The voice... It's calling me... I need to go....</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_psih_talk_lisiy_111111">
		<text>What are you saying?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_psih_talk_lisiy_1111111">
		<text>Gaah... My head... Ahh... It's the voice again!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_psih_talk_lisiy_11111111">
		<text>Calm down, friend. You're safe now.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_psih_talk_lisiy_111111111">
		<text>...Whispers... Whispers... Creak of swings... My daughter... I want to see her again so much, but I can't... I can't. That THING in my head is a monster, and it turned me into a monster. No, no! My friend, give this artifact to Barkeep. It's all I found there before It got into my head. Tell the Barkeep to give it to my daughter and wife. It's the least I can do for them...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_psih_talk_lisiy_1111111111">
		<text>Wait, what?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barmen_actor_give_ryaboy_art_0">
		<text>Barkeep, Spotty gave me this artifact..</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barmen_actor_give_ryaboy_art_1">
		<text>What artifact?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barmen_actor_give_ryaboy_art_11">
		<text>He gave me this artifact. He found it in the Radar. He told me to give it to you..</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barmen_actor_give_ryaboy_art_111">
		<text>To me?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barmen_actor_give_ryaboy_art_1111">
		<text>Yes. He said you should give it to his daughter and wife.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barmen_actor_give_ryaboy_art_11111">
		<text>Strange... Alright, give it to me.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barmen_actor_give_ryaboy_art_111111">
		<text>Here, it was his last wish.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barmen_deadcity_map_0">
		<text>A map of Dead City isn't interesting?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barmen_deadcity_map_1">
		<text>Oh, hell yes it is! Do you have one?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barmen_deadcity_map_11">
		<text>Yes, I've been there. What's your offer for the map?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barmen_deadcity_map_111">
		<text>That's incredible, Marked One. I've never seen anyone prove that they've been there. I'll pay you 30,000 rubles for it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barmen_deadcity_map_1111">
		<text>Deal! The map is yours.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barmen_deadcity_map_11111">
		<text>Here's the money. So, uh... Let's see... Um... So that's where the mercenaries are, and the bandits are here! What were you doing there, anyway?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barmen_deadcity_map_111111">
		<text>I was there on business.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barmen_deadcity_map_1111111">
		<text>Heh, well, soon stalkers will flock to this town.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barmen_deadcity_map_1112">
		<text>I'm sorry, I changed my mind.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barmen_deadcity_map_11121">
		<text>What, 30,000 is too little for a map?! Are you serious? I highly recommend you reconsider, and I doubt you'll find a better offer elsewhere. If you change your mind, come back here.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_ecolog_crush_professor_give_info_dp_0">
		<text>I'd like to know something.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_ecolog_crush_professor_give_info_dp_1">
		<text>What do you want to know?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_ecolog_crush_professor_give_info_dp_11">
		<text>Who are you and how did you end up here?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_ecolog_crush_professor_give_info_dp_111">
		<text>My name is Kruglov. I am a professor of biology, I study the Zone. Yesterday, for example, I found an animal of particular interest - Antropomorphus Dendromutantus Vulgaris. I mostly find and document new species of mutant animals, their traits and distinctive features. The information is then thoroughly studied and transferred to the outside world. Some of it, of course, goes to the Barkeep. My discoveries have helped to save the lives of many stalkers. I was just transporting the results of my latest research to the laboratory near Lake Yantar when the helicopter came under fire.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_ecolog_crush_professor_give_info_dp_1111">
		<text>Äà. Íàâåðíî, íåïðèÿòíî ñàäèòüñÿ íà "Äèêóþ òåððèòîðèþ" â ãîðÿùåì âåðòîëåòå.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_ecolog_crush_professor_give_info_dp_11111">
		<text>Íå òî ñëîâî!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_ecolog_crush_professor_give_info_dp_12">
		<text>Tell me about the Zone.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_ecolog_crush_professor_give_info_dp_121">
		<text>The Zone is a wonderful gift to humanity. Of course normal existence here is not possible due to the high radiation levels, and aggressive mutants. All of these things are obviously extremely dangerous but they are also things of great scientific value. The Zone is almost a natural experiment, a treasure for scientists! The extent to which humanity's knowledge could be increased through the study of the Zone is unfathomable. Technology, medicine, new plants- medical and edible, biotechnology, cures for incurable diseases...anything! Perhaps we can solve the food problem for the entire planet. If people didn't interfere, science could lead humanity into a new Golden Era!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_ecolog_crush_professor_give_info_dp_1211">
		<text>Duty thinks otherwise and even Freedom doesn't seem to want to help you.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_ecolog_crush_professor_give_info_dp_12111">
		<text>You're simply incapable of grasping the whole picture. Your "here and now" problems are far more important to you than the future of humanity!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_ecolog_crush_professor_give_info_dp_1212">
		<text>Maybe there is some use in studying the Zone.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_ecolog_crush_professor_give_info_dp_12121">
		<text>So you understand that too? It's wonderful to discover that there are those among you who are not narrow-minded practical people. I've always said it's important to look at the whole set of issues from a broader perspective, to distance ourselves from the simple human measures. Even if the Zone has done harm to humanity, it can still be of great use to us!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_ecolog_crush_professor_give_info_dp_13">
		<text>Why is Freedom looking for this information?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_ecolog_crush_professor_give_info_dp_131">
		<text>I hope this doesn't offend you, but many stalkers are like children. They are seriously affected by things they find out. Just think of all these legends about a Monolith that grants wishes. What a joke! The problem is that these children play their games with real weapons and cause death. Childish people are often annoyed about the fact that someone doesn't share everything with them, including information that is not meant for them. There are no limits in the use of force. They shoot without thinking and kill those who study the Zone. They believe that this information will allow them to open the way to the center of the Zone. They're fools, dangerous and naive fools!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_ecolog_crush_professor_give_info_dp_1311">
        <text>I wouldn't let legends go so easily. Someone risked their lives to bring this information to light.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="bar_ecolog_crush_professor_give_info_dp_14">
		<text>I need to decipher some very important documents. Do you know who can help me with this?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_ecolog_crush_professor_give_info_dp_141">
		<text>Decipher the documents? Hmm... You'd better ask Sakharov, he's in the mobile lab in Yantar.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_ecolog_crush_professor_give_info_dp_15">
		<text>Unfortunately I have to go. Good luck.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_ecolog_crush_professor_start_101">
		<text>Messer, stop them or they'll kill us!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_ecolog_crush_professor_start_1011">
		<text>Sit tight. We'll deal with them.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_ecolog_crush_professor_start_10111">
		<text>OK.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_ecolog_crush_professor_start_1012">
		<text>Let's move. We'll try to break through...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_ecolog_crush_professor_start_10121">
		<text>Let's hurry up.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_ecolog_crush_professor_start_11">
		<text>Stalker, I'm begging you! I don't know who you are, but please, help us! We were returning from Yantar when these anarchists shot down our helicopter. I heard that they are looking for information but I know they'll kill us. Help me get to the lake and I'll tell you everything I know about what you call the Brain Scorcher. The Barkeep will pay you well.</text> <!-- test -->
	</string>
	<string id="bar_ecolog_crush_professor_start_111">
		<text>OK. I'll try to help.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_ecolog_crush_professor_start_1111">
		<text>Thank you, stalker. I am not much of a fighter but I know the way so I'll lead and you cover us.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_ecolog_crush_professor_start_112">
		<text>No, I'm not going to get a bullet. Try to get out of here yourself.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_ecolog_crush_professor_start_1121">
		<text>No. I am sure you don't mean that. I'll never make it out of here alone. If you change your mind, I'll be here...if I live.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_ecolog_crush_professor_start_113">
		<text>Wait, what about the information?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_ecolog_crush_professor_start_1131">
		<text>What about the information?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_ecolog_crush_professor_start_11311">
		<text>What about it?! If they find out that I helped you escape, then we're both in trouble. And I'm sure they'll get their hands on it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_ecolog_crush_professor_start_113111">
		<text>I'll destroy it if they attack!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_ecolog_crush_professor_start_1131111">
		<text>No, it's too risky, you might not make it!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_ecolog_crush_professor_start_11311111">
		<text>And what do you suggest?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_ecolog_crush_professor_start_113111111">
		<text>I have a plan! You were taking this information somewhere, weren't you?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_ecolog_crush_professor_start_1131111111">
		<text>We were.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_ecolog_crush_professor_start_11311111111">
		<text>Let's do this: I'm gonna take this flash drive, sneak past the Freedom fighters, and take it to where it belongs. Then I'll come back to your rescue. What do you think?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_ecolog_crush_professor_start_113111111111">
		<text>Umm... this is the first time I've met you, and you're asking me to just hand you this sensitive information.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_ecolog_crush_professor_start_1131111111111">
		<text>It's up to you.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_ecolog_crush_professor_start_11311111111111">
		<text>Well, on the one hand, maybe you're right... I haven't much choice. Okay, I'll give it to you, but remember, this is very important information, and it should never get into the dirty paws of Freedom anarchists! I promised to give this flash drive to the Barkeep from the Stalker bar. He'll pay you well for it if you bring it to him. I'm counting on you. Also, come back soon, help us get out of here alive. We're not going to make it on our own. We are scientists, our business is scientific expeditions and laboratories...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_ecolog_crush_professor_start_113111111111111">
		<text>Okay. Okay. I will do everything in my power!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_ecolog_crush_professor_start_21">
		<text>Hurry, we have to get out of here quickly.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_ecolog_crush_professor_start_211">
		<text>I changed my mind. Let me escort you out of here first, and then I'll take the flash drive.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_ecolog_crush_professor_start_212">
		<text>I'm sorry, professor, but I couldn't keep the flash drive, they took it from me. But they let you go. Come on, let's get out of here.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_ecolog_crush_professor_start_2121">
		<text>Goddamn it, I can't believe they got their hands on that information. That could be the end of my career. Well... you saved our lives, and I'm grateful for that. I'm not a fighter, but I know the way so I'll lead, and you cover us on the way.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_ecolog_crush_professor_start_213">
		<text>Okay, I took the flash drive to Barkeep. Now we can get out of here.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_ecolog_crush_professor_start_214">
		<text>Let's go!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_ecolog_crush_professor_start_31">
		<text>Phew! Have we really made it to safety? At last! Thank you so much for your help. I am in your debt but for now please accept this flash drive. It contains the results of my latest expedition. I am sure the Barkeep would pay well for it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_ecolog_crush_professor_start_32">
		<text>Ugh. Are we safe? Finally. Thank you for your help. I owe you one. That flash drive I gave you contains the results of our last expedition. I'm sure the Barkeep will pay well for this information.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_ecolog_crush_professor_start_33">
		<text>Ugh. Are we safe? Finally. Thank you for your help. I owe you one. It is a pity, of course, that the results of the last expedition fell into their hands. But life is more important than that.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_ecolog_crush_professor_start_311">
		<text>Yes, we're here.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_ecolog_crush_professor_start_3111">
		<text>Messer, if you visit our mobile laboratory, we will give you a scientific suit.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_ecolog_crush_professor_start_31111">
		<text>We'll see.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_ecolog_crush_professor_start_41">
		<text>Hello, stalker. Allow me to express my gratitude on behalf of global science!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_ecolog_crush_professor_start_51">
		<text>Messer, stop them or they'll kill us!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_ecolog_crush_professor_start_511">
		<text>Sit tight. We'll deal with them.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_ecolog_crush_professor_start_5111">
		<text>OK.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_ecolog_crush_professor_start_512">
		<text>Let's move. We'll try to break through...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_ecolog_crush_professor_start_5121">
		<text>Let's go.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_ecolog_crush_professor_start_61">
		<text>Messer, stop them or they'll kill us!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_ecolog_crush_professor_start_611">
		<text>Sit tight. We'll deal with them.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_ecolog_crush_professor_start_6111">
		<text>OK, I'll wait here.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_ecolog_crush_professor_start_612">
		<text>Let's move. We'll try to break through...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_ecolog_crush_professor_start_6121">
		<text>OK, let's hurry.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_ecolog_crush_professor_start_71">
		<text>Be careful with the Burner, Messer. My suit will protect me but you'd best avoid it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_ecolog_crush_professor_start_711">
		<text>Thanks for your advice.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_ecolog_crush_professor_start_91">
		<text>Hurry, Messer. Now is not the time to talk.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_ecolog_dialog_11">
		<text>Stalker, talk to professor Kruglov, help him get out.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_ecolog_dialog_21">
		<text>It's over. They killed Kruglov!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_svoboda_dialog_0">
		<text>Come to Wolfhound, our leader, he's got a job for you there.</text>
	</string>
    <string id="bar_svoboda_volkodav_start_11">
        <text>Hey, stalker. I am Wolfhound, the leader of this pack of dogs. I think you can help us.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_svoboda_volkodav_start_21">
        <text>How's it going?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_svoboda_volkodav_start_31">
        <text>We remember your help, Marked One. Why did you come?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_svoboda_volkodav_start_41">
        <text>Yes, you're a monster. Take some time to think about joining my group. We need such people.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_svoboda_volkodav_start_51">
        <text>Hey, man. We need one thing; a small flash drive. Did you happen to come across it?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_svoboda_volkodav_start_61">
        <text>And you, man, how come? Get out of here, run!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_svoboda_volkodav_start_71">
        <text>You see, you're not from my unit, but get ready because soon the attack will start.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_svoboda_volkodav_start_81">
        <text>I'm busy, I don't have time to talk.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_svoboda_volkodav_start_91">
        <text>Like what?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_svoboda_volkodav_give_quest_dp_0">
        <text>Why should I help?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_svoboda_volkodav_give_quest_dp_1">
        <text>Do you know who caused the appearance of The Zone? Egghead assholes like these, that's who. I'm taking their top secret data that their government will hide from the public. Fuck these assholes. Turns out they had a good pilot; he managed to land the helicopter after it took a rocket, so they still have some well armed guards.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_svoboda_volkodav_give_quest_dp_11">
        <text>And what are you gonna do?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_svoboda_volkodav_give_quest_dp_111">
        <text>I have strict orders to obtain the information that they're carrying. But we don't have to fight. You're neutral, you can go negotiate on my behalf. They're trapped and they know it, and they're well aware that the clock is ticking because when night falls, shit goes to hell around here. Tell them how it is, get them to give up the info, and then maybe even these assholes will survive.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_svoboda_volkodav_give_quest_dp_1111">
        <text>Let's say they don't give it to me, then what? Or vice versa, what would you offer me if I brought you this information?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_svoboda_volkodav_give_quest_dp_11111">
        <text>I don't really care how you get it. Go ahead and shoot them all, my guys will even cover for you. Don't worry about the payment, we'll pay you back as expected, and you'll be on good terms with Freedom. Such opportunities don't just happen.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_svoboda_volkodav_give_quest_dp_111111">
        <text>Alright. I'll try to get the information.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_svoboda_volkodav_give_quest_dp_1111111">
        <text>Just bear in mind that we won't wait long. And don't lie to us, otherwise that'll be the last thing you ever do.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_svoboda_volkodav_give_quest_dp_111112">
        <text>Wait, I will not interfere.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_svoboda_volkodav_give_quest_dp_1111121">
        <text>Then get out of the way, soon things will get hot.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_svoboda_volkodav_kill_research_0">
        <text>I prefer living as well.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_svoboda_volkodav_kill_research_1">
        <text>So, where is the information?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_svoboda_volkodav_kill_research_11">
        <text>Here it is.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_svoboda_volkodav_kill_research_111">
        <text>You did your part, now listen to me. I don't carry valuable things with me in the field. Go to the bar and go to the type that sells information. He'll give you the money that's owed. Freedom remembers those who help us.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_svoboda_volkodav_kill_research_12">
        <text>No way. Do it yourself.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_svoboda_volkodav_kill_research_121">
        <text>Okay, let's assume you've done your part, now listen here. I don't carry valuable things with me in the field. You'll go to the bar and talk to the type that sells information. He'll give you the money that's owed. Freedom remembers those who help us.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_svoboda_volkodav_request_dp_0">
        <text>About the job...</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_svoboda_volkodav_request_dp_1">
        <text>Well?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_svoboda_volkodav_request_dp_11">
        <text>Almost like you predicted. Here is the information.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_svoboda_volkodav_request_dp_111">
        <text>Well there it is. No needless deaths, so you can sleep well tonight. You've done your part, now listen here. I don't carry valuable things with me in the field. You'll go to the bar and talk to the type that sells information. He'll give you the money that's owed. Freedom remembers those who help us.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_svoboda_volkodav_request_dp_1111">
        <text>Deal. What about scientists?</text>
    </string>
	<string id="bar_svoboda_volkodav_request_dp_11111">
		<text>What about them? We have the information, we don't need those eggheads anymore... If you want, get them out of here. Heh... I told you those assholes might survive. Whaddya know? They survived.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_svoboda_volkodav_request_dp_111111">
		<text>Alright.</text>
	</string>
    <string id="bar_svoboda_volkodav_request_dp_12">
        <text>I haven't got it yet.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_svoboda_volkodav_request_dp_121">
        <text>Hurry up, time is short.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_svoboda_volkodav_request_dp_13">
        <text>I have very urgent business, Wolfhound. Sorry but I can't help you.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_svoboda_volkodav_request_dp_131">
        <text>Whatever, kid. Just remember that you missed your chance to earn the favor of Freedom.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_svoboda_volkodav_noquest_0">
        <text>A flash drive?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_svoboda_volkodav_noquest_1">
        <text>Yes, a flash drive. You know, where information is digitally stored. Now answer my question.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_svoboda_volkodav_noquest_11">
        <text>Yes, we have one.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_svoboda_volkodav_noquest_111">
        <text>Let's make an exchange. You give me the flash drive, and then you get walk away from this place. You won't like the other option.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_svoboda_volkodav_noquest_112">
        <text>I have an assignment from Lukash himself to deliver this flash drive.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_svoboda_volkodav_noquest_1111">
        <text>Agreed.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_svoboda_volkodav_noquest_11111">
        <text>What a clever Stalker. Consider yourself reborn today.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="bar_svoboda_volkodav_noquest_11112">
        <text>Thank you for the help! I'll tell Lukash that you helped us.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_svoboda_volkodav_noquest_111111">
        <text>How kind you are. I'll remember that.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_svoboda_volkodav_noquest_1112">
        <text>No, man, I need that information too. It won't work.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_svoboda_volkodav_noquest_11121">
        <text>You have done a foolish thing. Take it!</text>
    </string>
	<string id="bar_svoboda_volkodav_noquest_11122">
        <text>You have done a foolish thing.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_svoboda_volkodav_noquest_111211">
        <text>Oh, you bastard!</text>
    </string>
	<string id="bar_svoboda_volkodav_noquest_111221">
        <text>Well, okay.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_svoboda_volkodav_noquest_12">
        <text>Didn't find it. What's on it?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_svoboda_volkodav_noquest_121">
        <text>Information that we're interested in. It does not concern you. Don't let me keep you. Goodbye.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_svoboda_volkodav_info_dp_0">
        <text>I would like to know something.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_svoboda_volkodav_info_dp_1">
        <text>What?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_svoboda_volkodav_info_dp_11">
        <text>Tell me about the Freedom faction.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_svoboda_volkodav_info_dp_111">
        <text>They believe that The Zone should be free to everyone. They take an active stance against the government and anyone else who wants to lock down The Zone and keep it contained. They see it as a gift to humanity. This puts them in direct opposition with Duty.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_svoboda_volkodav_info_dp_1111">
        <text>I would like to join Freedom. How can I do this?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_svoboda_volkodav_info_dp_11111">
        <text>Come to our leader, he will decide. Perhaps you'll be given some kind of task that you'll need to complete first.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_svoboda_volkodav_info_dp_111111">
        <text>Thanks for the info.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_svoboda_volkodav_info_dp_1112">
        <text>Why are you fighting with Duty?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_svoboda_volkodav_info_dp_11121">
        <text>They're your typical closed minded ignorant selfish assholes who want to destroy The Zone, and they don't listen to reason. Destroy The Zone? Medical miracles are made here! At this rate, we'll probably cure cancer in the next 10 years thanks to The Zone! Unless Duty actually succeeds, those fucking retards. They're just like the government; they want to control everything. Only they're even dumber, since every government sees value in The Zone, but Duty doesn't.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_svoboda_volkodav_info_dp_111211">
        <text>Hmm...</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_svoboda_volkodav_info_dp_12">
        <text>Who are you and what are you doing?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_svoboda_volkodav_info_dp_121">
        <text>Like I said, call me Wolfhound. I commanded a division in Freedom called "Dogs". Before The Zone came about, I was a well paid Mercenary. I've been to Afghanistan, Bosnia, Iraq, in a dozen hot spots, where I gained invaluable experience, a dozen scars, and two steel ribs.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_svoboda_volkodav_info_dp_1211">
        <text>Why did you go to the Zone?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_svoboda_volkodav_info_dp_12111">
        <text>In short, I was set up by one of my employers and barely got out alive. They want me dead, so I went somewhere where I'd be harder to track. There's good money to be made here, and good fighting, so everything has worked out.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_svoboda_volkodav_info_dp_121111">
        <text>Yes, The Zone is not a place for sissies.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_svoboda_volkodav_info_dp_13">
        <text>Who are the "Dogs"?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_svoboda_volkodav_info_dp_131">
        <text>"Dogs" is my pride. We're a special operations detachment of Freedom. Follow me into the fire, and when the smoke dies down only corpses will remain. Every fighter has personally selected. I don't just take anyone; whoever wants to join us has to prove themselves, and believe me, they will be pushed to the limit. Most will break, only the toughest can make it.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_svoboda_volkodav_info_dp_1311">
        <text>I understand.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_svoboda_volkodav_info_dp_14">
		<text>I changed my mind.</text>
    </string>


;ãîâíîïåðåâîä
	<string id="ros_bandit_stranger_11">
		<text>Man, help me!? There's no such thing, in general, we found a mountain of different artifacts, and to carry out can't. And you have a backpack, as I see. Come on, will you help us to bring artifacts to the right place, and we will give you to choose any artifact for yourself. Ok?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ros_bandit_stranger_21">
		<text>The artifacts are marked on the map.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ros_bandit_stranger_111">
		<text>Well, I agree. Where should I go?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ros_bandit_stranger_1111">
		<text>Well, I marked on the map.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ros_bandit_stranger_112">
		<text>No, not now.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ros_bandit_stranger_1121">
		<text>If decide, come.</text>
	</string>

</string_table>
